<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BodyCopy xmlns:cmis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/core/200908/" xmlns:cmisra="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/restatom/200908/" xmlns:sf="urn:telerik:sitefinity:cmis"><p><strong>By Steven McElhiney<br /> CEO<br /> <a
        href="https://www.captive.com/art-market/sponsors/profiles/ewi-re-inc">EWI Re,
        Inc</a>.</strong></p> <p>The following framework introduces a
        single-parent captive insurance company, walks through a time-tested approach for successful
        captive optimization, and overlays this approach with key success factors that may be
        integrated to achieve long-term economic value and superior risk control
        attributes.</p> <h3><strong>Captive Insurer
        Background</strong></h3> <p>The following discussion relates to a 30-year
        Vermont single-parent captive that is part of a global Fortune 1000 conglomerate based in
        Texas with operating units based in North America and the European Union. The underlying
        business units are involved in the chemicals, specialty steel, industrial manufacturing, and
        mining market segments. By their nature, these business segments present unusual risk
        exposures and a high inherent level of risk for both frequency- and severity-type events
        involving property and casualty exposures.</p> <p> <br /> The captive is
        rated by A.M. Best and is currently used only as respects the global property (with
        appropriate loss limits based on a number of factors including business operations,
        modeling, engineering analysis, and actuarial studies) and global casualty needs of the
        parent company. There is no material nonaffiliated business in the captive currently, and a
        100 percent reinsurance strategy is utilized for both of these placements. The captive
        solely utilizes a panel of highly rated and Vermont Department of Financial
        Regulation-approved global reinsurers representing the largest and most financially secure
        groups available.</p> <p>Over the long-term track record of the captive, the
        sponsor (parent company) has been able to achieve a number of coverage enhancements over
        time and the captive has produced over $25 million in economic value over this period from
        its favorable underwriting track record.<br /> <br /> The captive has taken a US
        taxpayer election since its inception and provides no additional tax advantages to the owner
        than would a traditional insurance program. The genesis and focus of this captive is a pure
        risk management one, rather than a financial, investment, or tax focus. This strategy and
        philosophy have been a critical success factor for the captive.</p> <p>This
        captive is internally staffed by a team of highly qualified career insurance and risk
        professionals who manage the captive according to "best practices" protocols and procedures
        that are utilized by insurers. Internal staffing is supplemented with a number of
        industry-respected service providers (e.g., captive manager, actuary, investment adviser,
        reinsurance intermediary, and a Big 4 accounting firm). The captive operates under strict
        control guidelines and has active board oversight.</p> <h3><strong>How It
        Works</strong></h3> <p><strong>How does your captive provide
        coverages needed for the particular business?</strong></p> <p>Given the
        investment that has been undertaken in this captive vehicle, it is our overarching
        philosophy to utilize this tool as broadly as possible in our overall risk transfer program.
        Thus, we tend to approach each renewal as if it is a "fresh piece" of paper. We look at
        market conditions as to whether we wish to access the traditional primary market or to
        change our retention strategy relative to the 100 percent reinsurance programs that are
        currently in place. This may be a function of market conditions and varying appetites by
        insurers or reinsurers.</p> <p>We utilize two manuscripted global policies for
        all controlled affiliate business entities and units within the consolidated group. These
        manuscripted policies often provide for broader protections or lower deductibles or higher
        sublimits than what might be found in a traditional commercial insurance program.<br
        /> <br /> It has been our experience that global reinsurers tend to have a broader
        appetite for some of our risk exposures than would traditional insurers on a primary basis.
        This coverage enhancement feature has had an incalculable value to our organization over the
        past 30 years as certain risk incidents have been "covered" (and supported by reinsurers)
        that would not have been in a traditional program.</p> <p>Given our conglomerate
        business model, we are often misclassified by traditional insurers who view the organization
        as a "chemical company" rather than an industrial conglomerate with a focus on a highly
        benign and low risk profile chemical product. In this context, we would be subjected to
        coverage limitations intended for more petroleum-based chemical manufacturers in a
        traditional program.</p> <p>As indicated, we currently provide a global property
        policy and a global casualty policy through the captive. A variety of exposures are insured,
        traditionally, outside of the captive. These include primary general liability and workers
        compensation as well as all management liability programs. We feel we are well served by
        utilizing a combination of traditional commercial insurers and policies as well as our
        captive-focused manuscripted policies.<br /> <br /> <strong>How does your
        captive save money on&amp;nbsp;insurance&amp;nbsp;for its single-parent
        owner?</strong></p> <p>All other things held equal, there is a minimal
        cost savings that arises from accessing the reinsurance market directly versus commercial
        insurance. Assuming identical loss costs, reinsurers may have a 1 to 2 percent cost
        advantage over traditional commercial insurers due to lower operating expenses.<br />
        <br /> More so, the financial advantages that we enjoy from our captive arise from the
        economies of scale that are achieved by buying cover for a variety of entities in one
        consolidated purchase via our global programs and the streamlined deductibles as well as the
        reduced administrative burden that presents. Also, as previously mentioned, the broader
        coverage enhancements afforded under a fully reinsured program provide an additional and
        incalculable economic value to our organization.</p> <p>For a single-parent
        captive such as ours, the key economic drivers for profitability over time have been the
        retention of profitable underwriting results coupled with the investment returns garnered on
        loss reserves. This value accretion, over a long term (like our 30-year experience), has
        produced substantial economic value to the organization. Much of this value would have
        inured to traditional insurance companies had we not formed a captive. In addition, it is
        our strong position that a captive vehicle heightens the risk management process within a
        complex organization and that this continuous cycle tends to drive better loss results over
        time.</p> <p><strong>How does your captive create competition for
        commercial insurers so that they reduce their prices and offer better
        coverage?</strong></p> <p>We do not see much of a nexus on this issue.
        Many of the insurance counterparties that we utilize in reinsuring our captive program are
        also large primary insurers. For example, we utilize Allianz, XL Catlin, and Chubb as
        reinsurers of our programs. All of these insurers would also be available to insure our
        needs on a traditional primary basis, albeit through different profit centers. Our captive
        utilization provides them with another portal to access our business to facilitate risk
        tailoring.</p> <p>Thus, we do not necessarily see the captive space as being a
        strong competitor to traditional markets. Rather, an alternative risk program simply
        provides another platform for commercial insurers to see the same risks in a different
        structural form. Our business continues to be syndicated in the global insurance market,
        with the addition of some new risk counterparties in Bermuda, the United Kingdom, and the
        European Union that would not be involved in a traditional insurance
        program.&amp;nbsp;</p> <p><strong>What, if any, coverages are provided by
        your captive that are not available or are cost-prohibitive in the commercial
        market?</strong></p> <p>It has been our experience that there are no
        coverages that we need that are not available in the commercial market. Rather, our model,
        reinsurance of a manuscripted policy, provides some subtle coverage enhancements to
        traditional commercial covers through endorsements and other such approaches. Further, we
        have been able to gain coverage for mine exposures with this approach, an exposure usually
        viewed critically by most traditional insurers.</p> <p><strong>How does
        your captive help risk management?</strong></p> <p>The success that we
        have enjoyed with our captive is a result of our core focus on risk management and control.
        A captive is an evolution in an overall risk management process and provides the vehicle for
        the assumption of risk and more advanced risk transfer mechanisms. Clearly, the overall
        success of a captive is dependent on better-than-average risk and loss outcomes over
        time.<br /> <br /> A captive fosters the heightened organization awareness and
        focus needed to reduce the frequency and to mitigate the severity of claim events. The
        profits that are earned in the captive help to lower the overall organizational "cost of
        risk" metric as an offset to claims and other risk-related expenses.<br /> <br
        /> We feel our captive has provided an organizational profit center to capture risk
        expenses and overall outcomes and a centralized means to drive improved risk and safety
        processes through disparate business units, given our conglomerate holding company
        model.&amp;nbsp;</p> <p><strong>How does your captive create surplus over
        time so that it can take on more of its parent owner's risk?</strong></p>
        <p>Over the 30 years of our captive, we have enjoyed a more than 12 percent compounded
        annual growth rate (net of dividends) in capital accretion through the retention of
        underwriting profits and the investment income earned on loss reserves. This value accretion
        has served to grow our net risk-bearing capacity tremendously, and it provides a buffer to
        allow us to entertain larger risk retentions should extreme "hard market" conditions
        resurface.</p> <h3><strong>The Keys to Success</strong></h3>
        <p>Based on the foregoing discussion points, a variety of key success factors are
        necessary for the ongoing optimization of a single-parent captive vehicle, as
        follows.</p> <ul> <li> <p>Recognition that a captive is a long-term
        foray into the insurance risk-bearing sector. It is imperative that such a captive be
        operated as a prototypical insurance company with the following key attributes:</p>
        <ul> <li> <p>well-delineated mission, purpose, and operational plans in
        place;</p> </li> <li> <p>active and vibrant board
        oversight;</p> </li> <li> <p>a well-defined and appropriate
        underwriting approach relative to the level of capital in place and in view of potential
        risks; and</p> </li> <li> <p>a focus, exclusively, on the captive as
        first and foremost a risk management and long-term insurance-regulated entity. It needs to
        be operated in an appropriate manner to ensure that solvency is maintained and that risks
        are well understood and mitigated, using reinsurance as needed. A captive that is focused
        solely on the tax attributes, or one that takes undue investment risk or retains poorly
        analyzed and priced risks, has a high likelihood of failure.&amp;nbsp;</p> </li>
        </ul> </li> <li> <p>Benefits of tailored coverages</p>
        <ul> <li> <p>Our key to success over time has emanated from having
        customized coverage provided by the captive. Thus, broadened protection is provided
        vis-&amp;agrave;-vis traditional fully insured solutions. In other words, the "magic" of
        manuscripting coverage is a key factor.</p> </li> </ul> </li>
        <li> <p>Long-term partnering relationships</p> <ul> <li>
        <p>Fundamentally, reinsurance should be utilized in a long-term partnering approach.
        Reinsurance should be purchased for reasons beyond capacity but more so as a means to
        utilize your panel in a manner that improves the degree of protection generally as well as
        the risk culture.</p> </li> <li> <p>Likewise, long-term
        relationships with various other service providers (e.g., third-party administrators,
        captive managers, investment advisers, actuaries) work best when viewed with a long-term
        partnering prism.</p> </li> </ul> </li> <li>
        <p>Application of "insurance operator" philosophies, strategies, and practices, such
        as the following.</p> <ul> <li> <p>Running a captive as a
        prototypical "A" rated entity with the guidelines in place suggested by A.M. Best and
        others</p> </li> <li> <p>Having a sound analytical understanding of
        the drivers of loss and the risk/return trade-off associated with retained risk given the
        inherently limited capital of a captive</p> </li> <li> <p>Utilizing
        reinsurance as needed to mitigate risks and protect solvency and minimize
        volatility</p> </li> <li> <p>Establishing a rigorous and thorough
        oversight process as provided by an involved board and captive manager</p> </li>
        </ul> </li> </ul> <p>Taken together, we feel that a
        captive&amp;mdash;when operated in a manner suggested in this article&amp;mdash;will
        invariably be highly successful and a long-term generator of economic value and superior
        risk control attributes.<br /> <br /> <strong><em>Steven M.
        McElhiney,&amp;nbsp;</em></strong><em>pictured above,&amp;nbsp;is the
        president and CEO of EWI Re, Inc., a subsidiary of NL Industries, Inc. (NYSE: NL), and a
        member of the Contran Corporation group of companies. He also serves as the chief risk
        officer for Contran Corporation, which is a global, privately owned holding company that,
        through wholly owned and majority-owned subsidiaries, controls four public companies and a
        number of privately owned companies. Contran Corporation is primarily involved with
        operations in chemicals, component parts, steel, and waste management. Mr. McElhiney is also
        the president of Tall Pines Insurance Company of Vermont (Contran Corporation's captive
        insurance company) and chairman of EWI Re (UK), Ltd., EWI Re's London-based subsidiary. Mr.
        McElhiney has an MBA in corporate finance and a BS, cum laude, from the University of
        Southern California. He attended graduate-level executive financial and management programs
        at Northwestern University's Kellogg School of Management and the University of Michigan's
        Ross School of Business. Mr. McElhiney authored <a
        href="[f669d9a7-009d-4d83-ddaa-000000000002]04a449de-0e2e-645a-bd90-ff0000ef0c73"></a></em><a
        href="[f669d9a7-009d-4d83-ddaa-000000000002]04a449de-0e2e-645a-bd90-ff0000ef0c73">Fundamentals
        of Reinsurance and Reinsurance Markets</a><em><a
        href="[f669d9a7-009d-4d83-ddaa-000000000002]04a449de-0e2e-645a-bd90-ff0000ef0c73"></a>
        for IRMI in 2012.</em></p></BodyCopy>