<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BodyCopy xmlns:cmis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/core/200908/" xmlns:cmisra="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/restatom/200908/" xmlns:sf="urn:telerik:sitefinity:cmis"><p>The recent spate of natural disasters has focused a spotlight on catastrophic
        losses. &amp;ldquo;Captive insurance,&amp;rdquo; says JLT Insurance Management&amp;rsquo;s
        (JLTIM's) Anne Marie Towle, &amp;ldquo;can play an important role in helping organizations
        defray some of the related financial losses."</p> <p>&amp;ldquo;Companies using
        their captives to insure a portion of quake and wind losses in California and wind and flood
        losses in coastal regions are becoming more common,&amp;rdquo; says Towle, executive vice
        president and Consulting Practice leader with JLTIM. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen some
        companies with high-wind deductibles of up to 10 percent and others that have to pay $1
        million to $5 million out of pocket before commercial insurance kicks in. Captive insurance
        is often an appropriate way for large organizations to fund these first-dollar
        losses.&amp;rdquo;</p> <p>Towle gives an example of a company with a $10 million
        cat-loss deductible. This company might use a captive, a commercial solution, or a
        combination of the two for initial losses. Another utilization strategy is having the
        company buy $100 million of catastrophic reinsurance for excess losses. In exchange for
        participation in a cat-loss layer, the company might take a small quota share percentage of
        the $100 million of reinsurance coverage when pricing is ideal for the
        captive.&amp;nbsp;</p> <p>&amp;ldquo;Cat losses give companies an opportunity to
        use a captive to its fullest potential, providing them balance sheet stability,&amp;rdquo;
        says Towle. &amp;ldquo;A captive-centric strategy for cat losses eases the immediate impact
        to operations and provides the ability to smooth potential losses over
        time.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp;</p> <p><em>Anne Marie Towle is executive vice
        president, Captive Consulting Practice leader with JLTIM. Ms. Towle was previously senior
        captive consultant, senior vice president for Willis Towers Watson. A Captive Review Power
        50 in 2017 and 2016, she also served Fortune 500 insurance companies as a manager of tax
        with KPMG and E&amp;amp;Y.</em></p> <em>Recently, Ms. Towle was the
        conference chair of the 2017 Vermont Captive Insurance Association Annual Conference and
        serves on the curriculum committee as an instructor and as a board member for the
        International Center for Captive Insurance Education.</em></BodyCopy>