<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BodyCopy xmlns:cmis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/core/200908/" xmlns:cmisra="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/restatom/200908/" xmlns:sf="urn:telerik:sitefinity:cmis"><p>What questions should&amp;nbsp;you be asking your investment manager but
        probably are not? Alton Cogert, president and chief executive officer of <a
        href="http://www.saai.com/">Strategic Asset Alliance</a>, recently posted
        a&amp;nbsp;<a
        href="http://www.saai.com/blog/2016/09/15/the-four-unasked-questions-you-should-ask-your-investment-manager/">blog</a>&amp;nbsp;on
        the Strategic Asset Alliance website offering the four&amp;nbsp;specific questions that will
        lead to a more meaningful and useful meeting with your investment manager.<span
        class="sfImageWrapper"
        data-sfref="[images|OpenAccessDataProvider]c72647de-0e2e-645a-bd90-ff0000ef0c73"><img
        width="125" height="156" title="alton-cogert" style="margin-top: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;
        margin-left: 10px; float: right;" alt="alton-cogert"
        src="[images|OpenAccessDataProvider]c72647de-0e2e-645a-bd90-ff0000ef0c73"
        displaymode="Original" /></span><br /> <br /> <span
        class="sfImageWrapper"
        data-sfref="[images|OpenAccessDataProvider]c72647de-0e2e-645a-bd90-ff0000ef0c73"></span>Mr.
        Cogert (pictured at right)&amp;nbsp;has granted Captive.com permission to share with our
        readers the thoughts he expressed in his September 15, 2016, blog post, as
        follows.</p> <h2>The Four Unasked Questions You Should Ask Your Investment
        Manager</h2> <p><strong><em>By <a
        href="mailto:acogert@saai.com">Alton Cogert</a></em></strong></p>
        <p>Submitted for your approval. A recent, probably typical, meeting with your
        investment manager.</p> <p>"Let me tell you," the investment manager says, "This
        financial environment is completely unprecedented. Globally, central banks are manipulating
        supply and demand of fixed income and equity securities."</p> <p>"Yes, we know,"
        you tell him, "but what can we do about these low interest rates? It seems that every time
        we meet our portfolio's book yield moves lower and lower."</p> <p>"Good
        question," he says, and then turns to his associate.</p> <p>"If you want to take
        more risk," she says, "we can get you more yield, but the result will just be a marginal
        improvement in how quickly that book yield goes lower. We have suggested a few ideas, but
        you have told us they don't fit your company's risk appetite."</p> <p>"That is
        true," you realize and the meeting drones on in its usual fashion. The economy, the
        portfolio, securities of interest, etc., etc. You exchange pleasantries and wish everyone
        safe travels back to their home base.</p> <p>After the meeting, sitting in your
        office, you start to think something may be missing.</p>
        <p><strong><em>"Did I ask the right
        questions?"</em></strong></p> <p>You probably did, but you may have
        missed a few questions that managers typically don't hear, but should, from their insurer
        clients.</p> <p>What should you be asking and why? Let's review four typically
        unasked questions.</p> <p><strong>1. Negative Rates&amp;mdash;What
        If?</strong></p> <p>You have probably read about negative interest rates
        and wondered, "How can that be? A government bond that we have to pay interest to the
        government in order to hold in the portfolio. Who in their right mind would invest in
        that?"</p> <p>Well, over 30 percent of sovereign debt, globally, now has a
        negative market interest rate.</p> <p>Or, how about corporate bonds with
        negative interest rates? It is happening now in Europe.</p> <p>Could this happen
        with US Treasuries? Or, could a company borrow at a negative interest rate in the United
        States? Did we ever expect rates to stay this low for this long?</p> <p>What
        does your investment manager think is the probability we might see negative rates in the
        United States? Could this be an unexpected consequence if the typically low probability of
        recession in manager's models occur? Is this something we should be considering in our
        planning? If so, how would we mitigate such an occurrence?</p>
        <p><strong>2. What Are Other Insurers Doing?</strong></p>
        <p>Some managers may have a better advantage than others at answering this question,
        simply because of their experience with managing insurer assets. And, even if they have that
        experience, it may not be broad enough or similar enough to your company to provide a useful
        answer. So, this might be a more difficult question to answer than you might
        think.</p> <p>In addition, some managers are affiliated with insurers. In those
        cases, they may (or may not) feel comfortable revealing what other asset classes their
        affiliated insurer is utilizing in the current environment.</p>
        <p><strong>3. What Would You Ask If You Were in Our
        Shoes?</strong></p> <p>This may be my all-time favorite question that I
        once heard a client ask a manager.</p> <p>To properly answer it, the manager has
        to put themselves in your shoes, which should take some thought, and then, using their
        experience and knowledge, determine what they would really want to know.</p>
        <p>Too many times, someone who is asked this question will merely parrot back what
        they had been saying was important all along. However, by asking them "why" they said what
        they said, and then "why" again and, perhaps, again, you might find a rather interesting
        idea at the core of their initial response. This can be time consuming, but it can also be
        enlightening.</p> <p><strong>4. How Do You Compare, Quantitatively and
        Qualitatively, to Your Peer Managers?</strong></p> <p>Insurers usually
        compare themselves to other insurer peers, and that certainly can be a worthwhile exercise.
        However, have you wondered how your manager compares to its peers?</p> <p>This
        is both an easy and difficult question for the manager to answer. </p> <p>Easy,
        because there is data available that can be properly presented by the manager to show how
        its performance is "in the top quartile," or something like that, of similar managers. In
        fact, data analytic companies that market such performance comparisons to the managers
        feature the ability to customize peer groups, so the manager can be seen in the best
        possible light. (Of course, there is always the issue of comparing performance from one
        insurer's account to another due to differing constraints and mandates.)</p>
        <p>Difficult, because fairly comparing your manager to other managers is much more
        complex than just looking at performance. There are numerous other quantitative and
        qualitative factors that should be considered. For example, we utilize&amp;nbsp;<a
        href="http://www.insurercio.com/node/454102">Manager Select </a>when performing a
        manager peer analysis, or a manager search (whether an active or just an initial fiduciary
        search). The traits we find most useful for comparison include organizational background,
        investment team, experience managing insurance assets, investment process and performance
        (including attribution).</p> <p>Manager Select allows us to easily run these
        analyses. You can preview Manager Select&amp;nbsp;<a
        href="http://www.insurercio.com/node/454102">here</a> and begin comparing your
        manager to its peers across these various attributes.</p> <p><strong>The
        Four Unasked Questions</strong></p> <p> At your next meeting with your
        investment manager, you might try asking one or more of these four unasked questions. Of
        course, they are not designed to be the only questions you ask. But, they can lead to a much
        more meaningful and useful meeting with your investment manager.<br /> <br />
        <em>(Photo of Alton Cogert, above right, is courtesy of
        Mr.&amp;nbsp;Cogert.)</em></p></BodyCopy>