<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BodyCopy xmlns:cmis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/core/200908/" xmlns:cmisra="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/restatom/200908/" xmlns:sf="urn:telerik:sitefinity:cmis"><p>A.M. Best has affirmed, according to a November 17, 2015, press release, the
        financial strength rating (FSR) of A (Excellent) and the issuer credit ratings (ICR) of "a"
        of Housing Authority Property Insurance, A Mutual Company (HAPI); Housing Authority Risk
        Retention Group, Inc. (HARRG); and their jointly owned subsidiary, Housing Enterprise
        Insurance Company, Inc. (all members of and together known as the HAI Group). The outlook
        for these ratings is stable.</p> <p>Concurrently, A.M. Best has affirmed the FSR
        of A- (Excellent) and the ICR of "a-" of Housing Specialty Insurance Company, Inc. (HSIC).
        The outlook for both ratings is stable.</p> <p>All companies are domiciled in
        Burlington, Vermont.</p> <p>View the <a
        href="https://www.housingcenter.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Full-Final-Annual-Report_2014.pdf"
        target="_blank">2014 Annual Report</a> and <a
        href="https://www.housingcenter.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Audited-Financials.pdf"
        target="_blank">financial audits</a> for the HAI Group companies. The Housing
        Authority Risk Retention Group surplus of $196 million ranks the captive as the fifth
        largest RRG. The RRG started operations in 1987.</p> <p>The press release went
        on to say that the ratings of the HAI Group acknowledge its excellent capitalization, very
        strong operating results, leading position, and proven expertise in the niche public housing
        authority market. A.M. Best deviated from its "Rating Members of Insurance Groups" criteria
        in regard to certain ownership limitations, which relate to the existence of a risk
        retention group within the HAI Group.</p> <p>The HAI Group provides property and
        liability coverage to public housing authorities and their affiliated operations throughout
        the United States, the press release continued. While retaining a large percentage of its
        member insureds and regularly adding new members, the group maintains a market share of
        about 40 percent of this segment on a per-unit basis. With its solid operating performance,
        the HAI Group has progressively built up its surplus through retained earnings as its
        underwriting leverage is very low. The group's underwriting results remain strong due to its
        focused and disciplined underwriting approach and conservative reserving. Over the years, it
        has increased rates when appropriate and withdrawn from problematic accounts and lines of
        business, such as workers compensation. In addition, the HAI Group's operating performance
        benefits significantly from effective enterprise risk management, its tax-efficient
        structure, and strong client relationships, which are supported by a number of customized
        programs and services. The ratings also recognize its management's conservative operating
        strategy, consistent with the member insureds' expectations. The group maintains a
        conservative investment portfolio and prudently utilizes reinsurance.</p>
        <p>Partially offsetting these positive rating factors is the group&amp;rsquo;s
        concentration of risk in the public housing authority sector, which magnifies the impact of
        market cycles and public policy and legislative changes, the press release stated.</p>
        <p>A.M. Best expects the HAI Group&amp;rsquo;s future operating performance to be
        stable and strong; as the stable earnings profile should support controlling its growth and
        business writings, which are consistent with its capital and surplus position.</p>
        <p>The ratings of HSIC reflect its strong capital position and the support it receives
        from the HAI Group, the press release said. HSIC is an excess and surplus lines insurer that
        will be providing a nontraditional insurance program to public and affordable housing
        providers throughout the United States, as well as a for-profit, property/casualty stock
        insurer, which was incorporated in Vermont on December 9, 2013. The company is jointly owned
        by HARRG and HAPI as a subsidiary.</p></BodyCopy>