<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BodyCopy>
        <p>All commercial insurance lines except workers compensation saw year-over-year increases
                in July, according to the IVANS Index, a regular premium renewal rate index compiled
                by IVANS insurance exchange service.</p>
        <p>Compared to July 2019, commercial auto, general liability, commercial property,
                businessowners policy (BOP), and umbrella coverages experienced premium renewal rate
                increases in July, while the average workers compensation premium decreased.</p>
        <p>July premium renewal rate changes included the following.</p>
        <ul>
                <li><strong>Commercial auto</strong>: 5.1 percent increase, up from a 4.63 percent
                        increase in June</li>
                <li><strong>BOP</strong>: 4.38 percent increase, down from a 4.64 percent increase
                        in June</li>
                <li><strong>General liability</strong>: 3.45 percent increase, up from a 3.36
                        percent increase in June</li>
                <li><strong>Commercial property</strong>: 5.42 percent increase, up from a 5.23
                        percent increase in June</li>
                <li><strong>Umbrella</strong>: 3.23 percent increase, down from a 3.56 percent
                        increase in June</li>
                <li><strong>Workers compensation</strong>: 2.66 percent decrease, down from a 2.49
                        percent decrease in June</li>
        </ul>
        <p>"Year-over-year, we continue to see the commercial lines premium renewal rates on the
                rise, with the exception of workers compensation," Brian Wood, vice president of
                Data Products Group, IVANS Insurance Services, said in a statement. "The data
                insights of the IVANS Index continues to demonstrate a hardening market and acts as
                further evidence of insurers taking rate to mitigate potential loss."</p>
        <p>Released on a monthly basis, the IVANS Index analyzes more than 120 million data
                transactions to measure premium renewal rate change year-over-year across the US
                market.</p>
</BodyCopy>
