<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BodyCopy xmlns:cmis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/core/200908/" xmlns:cmisra="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/restatom/200908/" xmlns:sf="urn:telerik:sitefinity:cmis"><p>Strategic Risk Solutions (SRS) has announced that Andy Hulme has joined the
        captive management and consulting services provider as part of an expansion of its
        underwriting capabilities and services.</p> <p>Mr. Hulme most recently was chief
        underwriting officer for Builders Insurance Holdings, an insurance and reinsurance
        subsidiary of German construction company Hochtief. He will be based in the United Kingdom
        but will provide underwriting support to SRS clients globally.</p> <p>"Andy
        brings extensive experience in structuring and underwriting a broad range of coverages for
        captives,"&amp;nbsp;Brady Young, president and CEO of SRS, said in a statement. "His
        expertise will help our clients in both Europe and globally gain more from their
        captives."</p> <p>Prior to his time at Hochtief, Mr. Hulme was executive vice
        president of JLT Insurance Management in Bermuda and London.</p> <p>"I am
        excited to be returning to the captive management industry and working with a variety of
        clients to solve their risk financing needs," Mr. Hulme said. "SRS has built a strong
        captive business particularly in North America. I am looking forward to expanding the firm's
        underwriting and advisory services and growing the presence in Europe."</p> <p>
        "I worked with Andy at JLT in Bermuda and have tremendous respect for the creativity he
        brings to designing captive programs," said Richard Daley, managing director of SRS Bermuda.
        "His skills will complement SRS's existing US-based advisory services allowing us to expand
        the depth of those services and bring a unique combination of captive management services to
        our clients domiciled in Bermuda and elsewhere."</p></BodyCopy>