<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BodyCopy xmlns:cmis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/core/200908/" xmlns:cmisra="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/restatom/200908/" xmlns:sf="urn:telerik:sitefinity:cmis"><p><a href="http://wef.ch/risks2018"><em>The Global Risks Report
        2018</em></a>, published by the World Economic Forum, shares the perspectives of
        global experts and decision-makers on the most significant risks that face the world. The
        report illuminates the struggle to keep up with an accelerating pace of change and
        highlights numerous areas where systems are pushed to the brink, from extinction-level rates
        of biodiversity loss to mounting concerns about the possibility of new wars.</p>
        <p> The annual <em>Global Risks Perception Survey (GRPS)</em> asked nearly
        1,000 respondents for their views about the trajectory of risks in 2018; 59 percent of their
        answers pointed to an intensification of risks, compared with 7 percent pointing to
        declining risks.</p> <p> As in 2017 (annual reports are published each January),
        the environment was by far the greatest concern raised by experts. Among the 30 global risks
        the experts were asked to prioritize in terms of likelihood and impact, all five
        environmental risks<em>&amp;mdash;</em>extreme weather,&amp;nbsp;biodiversity
        loss and ecosystem collapse,&amp;nbsp;major natural disasters,&amp;nbsp;man-made
        environmental disasters, and&amp;nbsp;failure of climate-change mitigation and
        adaptation&amp;mdash;were ranked highly on both dimensions. Extreme weather events were seen
        as the single most prominent risk.</p> <p> The report says that the prospect of
        strong economic growth in 2018 presents leaders with a golden opportunity to address signs
        of severe weakness in many of the complex systems that underpin the world, such as
        societies, economies, international relations, and the environment.<br /> <br />
        Professor Klaus Schwab, founder and executive chairman, World Economic Forum, commented as
        follows.</p> <p style="margin-left: 40px;"> A widening economic recovery
        presents us with an opportunity that we cannot afford to squander, to tackle the fractures
        that we have allowed to weaken the world's institutions, societies, and environment. We must
        take seriously the risk of a global systems breakdown. Together we have the resources and
        the new scientific and technological knowledge to prevent this. Above all, the challenge is
        to find the will and momentum to work together for a shared future.</p> <p>
        According to the GRPS,&amp;nbsp;cyber threats<em>&amp;nbsp;</em>are growing in
        prominence, with&amp;nbsp;large-scale cyber attacks<em>&amp;nbsp;</em>ranked
        third in terms of likelihood, while&amp;nbsp;rising cyber dependency&amp;nbsp;is ranked as
        the second most significant driver shaping the global risks landscape over the next 10
        years.</p> <p>John Drzik, president of Global Risk and Digital, Marsh, said the
        following.</p> <p style="margin-left: 40px;"> Geopolitical friction is
        contributing to a surge in the scale and sophistication of cyber attacks. At the same time,
        cyber exposure is growing as firms are becoming more dependent on technology. While
        cyber-risk management is improving, business and government need to invest far more in
        resilience efforts if we are to prevent the same bulging "protection" gap between economic
        and insured losses that we see for natural catastrophes.</p> <p> The Federation
        of European Risk Management Associations (FERMA) and its members urge companies to use the
        economic recovery to invest in increasing their resilience. "We believe that an enterprise
        risk management process with leadership from a risk management professional gives
        organizations the most effective way to make these investment decisions," said FERMA
        President Jo Willaert.</p></BodyCopy>