<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BodyCopy xmlns:cmis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/core/200908/" xmlns:cmisra="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/restatom/200908/" xmlns:sf="urn:telerik:sitefinity:cmis"><p>Man-made risks like cyber crime, interstate conflicts, or market crashes are
        a bigger threat to economic output than natural disasters such as hurricanes, floods,
        earthquakes, and volcanoes, putting an estimated $320.1 billion of global gross domestic
        product (GDP) at risk on average each year, according to Lloyd's.<br /> <br />
        The&amp;nbsp;<em>Lloyd's City Risk Index</em>, built in collaboration with
        Cambridge University, measured the impact of 22 threats on 279 cities' projected economic
        output.&amp;nbsp;The index revealed that 279 cities across the world&amp;mdash;the key
        engines of global economic growth with a combined&amp;nbsp;GDP of $35.4
        trillion&amp;mdash;risk losing on average $546.5 billion in economic output annually
        (GDP@Risk) from all 22 threats. This comprises $320.1 billion to man-made risks and $226.4
        billion to natural catastrophes.</p> <p> The key trends identified by the index
        are as follows.</p> <ul> <li><span style="font-size: 13px;">Man-made
        threats are on the rise.&amp;nbsp;Man-made threats account for 59 percent of all global
        GDP@Risk. Financial market crash is identified as the biggest threat to the global economy,
        putting on average $103.3 billion in global economic output at risk per year. Reflecting the
        rising level of geopolitical instability around the world, the study indicates that
        interstate conflict is the second costliest peril&amp;mdash;totaling $80.0 billion in
        GDP@Risk.</span></li> <li><span style="font-size: 13px;">Climate
        change is still a major risk driver.&amp;nbsp;Climate-related risks together account for
        $123.0 billion of GDP@Risk, and this sum is expected to grow as extreme weather events
        become increasingly frequent and severe. The costliest climate events are windstorms, which
        account for $66.3 billion of GDP@Risk, and flood that puts a further $42.9 billion of
        economic output at risk.</span></li> <li><span style="font-size:
        13px;">The majority of risk is concentrated in a few cities.&amp;nbsp;The 10 cities with
        the highest GDP@Risk together face $126.8 billion in potential losses to economic output
        each year. This is almost a quarter of total GDP@Risk and more than the amount of GDP@Risk
        in Africa, the Middle East, and Latin America combined. This finding reflects the increasing
        concentration of wealth in certain geographic regions and, therefore, the vulnerability of
        the global economy to disruptive events.</span></li> <li><span
        style="font-size: 13px;">Building resilience is an urgent priority.&amp;nbsp;The index
        scores each city's resilience based on criteria such as funding for emergency services and
        insurance levels. If every city in the index were to improve its resilience to the highest
        level, then global GDP@Risk would decrease by as much as $73.4
        billion.</span></li> </ul> <p>Extreme events are rare but costly
        when they do take place. To reflect this fact, the index averages out these large losses to
        produce an annual average loss estimate: GDP@Risk.</p> <p>However, the actual
        losses from an extreme event in any given year could be much higher than this. An
        illustration is provided by Los Angeles where, according to the index, the average annual
        loss estimate for an earthquake is $2.7 billion GDP@Risk. However, according to the index,
        in an extreme scenario an earthquake in Los Angeles could cause the city to lose as much as
        $380.4 billion of GDP.<br /> <br /> Lloyd's Chairman Bruce Carnegie-Brown
        commented as follows.</p> <p style="margin-left: 40px;"> No city will ever be
        completely risk free. Disruptions will always occur, whether it is the result of a hurricane
        or a cyber attack. We have created this unique index to help cities around the world
        identify, understand, and quantify their exposure to risk, which will help them prioritize
        investments and build resilience.</p> <p style="margin-left: 40px;">The index
        shows that investing in resilience&amp;mdash;from physical flood defenses to digital
        firewalls and enhanced cyber security, combined with insurance&amp;mdash;will help
        significantly reduce the impact of extreme events on cities, improve economic stability, and
        enhance prosperity for all. I urge insurers, governments, and businesses to look at the
        index and work together to reduce these exposures by building more resilient infrastructure
        and institutions.</p> <p>Professor Daniel Ralph, academic director of Cambridge
        Center for Risk Studies at the University of Cambridge Judge Business School, added the
        following.</p> <p style="margin-left: 40px;"> One way of thinking about GDP@Risk
        is as the money a prudent city needs to put aside each year to cover the cost of risk
        events. <em>Lloyd's City Risk Index</em> helps governments, businesses, and the
        insurance sector understand the economic implications of a variety of man-made and natural
        risks and use the GDP@Risk metric to enhance their preparedness and resilience.</p>
        <p style="margin-left: 40px;">One of the most prominent features of the index is the
        worldwide rise in geopolitical risk, driven in large part by the threat of interstate
        conflict and civil unrest. We are likely to see this trend continue on a global
        level.</p></BodyCopy>