<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BodyCopy xmlns:cmis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/core/200908/" xmlns:cmisra="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/restatom/200908/" xmlns:sf="urn:telerik:sitefinity:cmis"><p>Global engineering insurance premiums for 2017 were estimated at around $21
        billion but have stagnated in recent years according to the
        latest&amp;nbsp;<em>sigma</em>&amp;nbsp;study from the Swiss Re Institute.
        Underwriting performance has deteriorated recently, with premium rates declining and claims
        rising in some construction sectors. Urbanization, the replacement of aging infrastructure,
        and the development of renewable energy sources should all promote construction spending and
        engineering insurance demand.</p> <p>New technologies could also lead to
        significant improvements in efficiency including enhanced monitoring, mitigation, and
        management of engineering-related risks, although they create new risks.</p>
        <p>Comprehensive data on engineering premiums are lacking in the market. Based on
        extensive research of available country-level sources, Swiss Re Institute estimates global
        engineering insurance premiums for 2017 were at around $21 billion. This represents roughly
        3 percent of total commercial insurance premiums (around $730 billion in 2017). Around half
        of the market is accounted for by project insurance, which protects against risks incurred
        during construction or installation of plants, buildings, and infrastructure.</p>
        <p>After rising rapidly through most of the 2000s as construction activity in a number
        of developing countries soared, global engineering premiums have stagnated in recent years.
        Construction spending as a percent of gross domestic product in many advanced markets
        remains below its pre-2008 financial crisis peak, while some key emerging markets are only
        slowly emerging from recent recessions. The European, Middle Eastern, and African region
        nonetheless continues to generate the largest share of global engineering premiums, mostly
        due to the popularity of operational covers such as machine breakdown and construction
        insurance (Figure 1).</p> <p><img
        src="[images|OpenAccessDataProvider]39ab4fde-0e2e-645a-bd90-ff0000ef0c73"
        data-displaymode="Original" class="img-responsive" style="width: 100%; vertical-align:
        middle; margin-top: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;" alt="Figure 1" title="Figure 1"
        /><strong style="font-size: 18px;">Structure of the Engineering Insurance Market Is
        Evolving</strong></p> <p> Diversification for large, complex engineering
        risks is achieved via a combination of national (e.g., retail), insurance, and wholesale
        co-re/insurance subscription markets. While London remains an important center for
        engineering and construction-related insurance, especially for high-value projects that are
        technically demanding to underwrite, increasingly engineering risks are being underwritten
        from the international hubs of Singapore, Dubai, and Miami. Domestic brokers are especially
        active in arranging insurance for local construction projects, while international brokers
        play a key role for complex projects that require specialist expertise and/or those where
        foreign funding is involved.</p> <h2><strong>Underwriting Performance Is
        Deteriorating</strong></h2> <p> Underwriting performance has deteriorated
        recently, with loss ratios edging higher and claims rising in some construction sectors due
        to lower quality control. Reported loss ratios likely understate the recent deterioration in
        underwriting profits. Because ultimate loss experience takes time to become fully developed,
        claim settlements are often delayed. Soft underwriting market conditions have also depressed
        engineering insurance pricing. Mike Mitchell, head of Property and Specialty Underwriting at
        Swiss Re, says, "Engineering premium rates have been declining for over a decade. Some
        engineering insurers' profit margins may already have been squeezed close to or below levels
        that are sustainable over the long term."</p> <h2><strong>The Growing Use
        of New Technologies in Construction</strong></h2> <p> The construction
        sector is beginning to adopt digital technology and processes. Start-up companies are an
        important part of the emerging innovation narrative. More than 400 constructech firms have
        formed since 2009, raising $2.9 billion in funding, many of which are focused on tools to
        improve construction management (Figure 2).</p> <p><img
        src="[images|OpenAccessDataProvider]1cab4fde-0e2e-645a-bd90-ff0000ef0c73"
        data-displaymode="Original" class="img-responsive" style="width: 100%; vertical-align:
        middle; margin-top: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;" alt="Figure 2" title="Figure 2" />While
        the use of digital technology could lead to significant improvements in efficiency,
        including enhanced monitoring, mitigation, and management of engineering-related risks, Mr.
        Mitchell says, "Technology also affects the nature of existing risks and brings with it new
        risks such as cyber. Insurers could see the severity of claims increase even if the
        frequency of accidents continues to fall." Product and process innovation will help insurers
        respond to the evolving risk and competitive landscape. In a digitally connected world,
        insurance may come to play more of a risk avoidance/mitigation role. This may ultimately
        require a more radical reconfiguration of engineering insurers' business models.</p>
        <h2><strong>Market Outlook for Engineering Insurance</strong></h2>
        <p> Beyond technological innovation, the outlook for engineering insurance is heavily
        influenced by prospective growth in the world economy. The ongoing cyclical economic upswing
        in advanced and developing markets in the near term should stimulate construction activity
        and insurance demand. Also, structural adjustments such as urbanization, the replacement of
        aging infrastructure, and the development of renewable energy sources should promote
        spending on construction. However, there is still uncertainty about how far some of these
        factors will translate into a material pick-up in premium growth.</p> <p> The
        English, German, French, and Spanish versions of
        the&amp;nbsp;<em>sigma&amp;nbsp;</em>No 2/2018, "Constructing the Future: Recent
        Developments in Engineering Insurance" are available electronically on Swiss Re Institute's
        website:&amp;nbsp;institute.swissre.com.</p></BodyCopy>