<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BodyCopy xmlns:cmis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/core/200908/" xmlns:cmisra="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/restatom/200908/" xmlns:sf="urn:telerik:sitefinity:cmis"><p>A team of students from the University of Southern California took
        first-place honors in the Captive Insurance Companies Association (CICA) 2020 college
        student essay contest, "Captive Insurance Solutions for Emerging Industries."</p>
        <p>Megan Moore (pictured above, left) and Natalie Kojababian (pictured above, right)
        were named the competition's winners during a webinar Tuesday hosted by <a
        href="[f669d9a7-009d-4d83-ddaa-000000000002]3bff3fde-0e2e-645a-bd90-ff0000ef0c73">Strategic
        Risk Solutions (SRS)</a>, sponsor of the CICA Essay Contest. The webinar featured the
        top three teams presenting their essays and fielding questions, followed by the announcement
        of the winners.</p> <p>The winning entry focused on using a group captive
        solution to provide liability insurance coverage for the cannabis industry. Ms. Moore and
        Ms. Kojababian shared a $2,500 prize as first-place winners.</p> <p>Second place
        in the competition featured a tie between the remaining two in the top three finalist teams.
        Noting that this year's competition saw an increase in entries, CICA President Dan Towle
        said that even more noteworthy was how close the final scores were. "In fact, when the
        essays were scored, the final two teams were in an exact tie in scoring," he said during the
        webinar.</p> <p>Tying for second place were Marissa Dias and Samantha Kane from
        St. Joseph's University, whose essay focused on using a risk retention group to address home
        healthcare industry risks, and Magda Olivas Carmona and Rudy Martinez of St. Mary's
        University, who proposed a group medical stop loss captive for the craft brewing industry.
        Each second-place team received a $1,500 prize.</p> <p>In a statement, Brady
        Young, CEO at SRS, said, "We're very pleased with the students' work and their willingness
        to dig in and learn about captive opportunities not only for today but for growing and
        emerging industries that can benefit from captive solutions."</p> <p>The
        students were originally scheduled to present their essays at CICA's 2020 International
        Conference in March, but the event was canceled due to the COVID-19 pandemic. </p>
        <p> "Writing your essay is one component of the contest. We also want to give the
        students the opportunity to present to industry organizations that might become their future
        employers," Mr. Towle said in a statement. "Today we were able to have them present
        and&amp;nbsp;celebrate their success."<br /> <br /> <em>(Photos of Ms.
        Moore and Ms. Kojababian above are courtesy of Captive Insurance Companies
        Association.)</em></p></BodyCopy>