<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BodyCopy xmlns:cmis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/core/200908/" xmlns:cmisra="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/restatom/200908/" xmlns:sf="urn:telerik:sitefinity:cmis"><p>American International Group, Inc. (AIG), has appointed Brian Duperreault as
        president, CEO, and director, effective May 14, 2017. Mr. Duperreault has resigned as
        chairman and CEO of Hamilton Insurance Group. Peter D. Hancock resigned
        as&amp;nbsp;AIG's&amp;nbsp;president, CEO, and director concurrent with Mr. Duperreault's
        appointment.</p> <p>Douglas M. Steenland, AIG's chairman of the board, said,
        "Brian is uniquely qualified to lead AIG at this important time. Brian has spent his entire
        career in insurance. He worked for AIG for 21 years at the start of his career, so he knows
        this company well. He was the CEO of ACE, one of our main competitors. He ran Marsh
        &amp;amp; McLennan Companies, one of AIG's largest broker partners. At Hamilton, he
        introduced cutting edge data science and analytics into the insurance business. He is a
        hands-on leader who has consistently delivered strong bottom-line results. He has
        demonstrated a passion for deploying new and innovative ways to serve clients. All of this
        will enable Brian to help AIG achieve its full potential to be the leading insurance
        company. </p> <p>"The Board and I want to thank Peter Hancock for his leadership
        in positioning AIG for the future. During his tenure, Peter set the course for the company
        to deliver higher quality, more sustainable earnings and dramatically reduced reserve risk.
        We are grateful for his leadership over the past seven years," Mr. Steenland
        continued.</p> <p>"It is a privilege to return and lead AIG," Mr. Duperreault
        said. "I look forward to building on AIG's nearly 100-year heritage as one of the world's
        leading insurers for its next century. </p> <p>"In my discussions with the Board
        and management team, I have been impressed with the progress made," he continued. "I look
        forward to working with AIG's global team to build on this momentum to grow the business,
        and continue delivering innovative solutions and extraordinary service to clients. I also
        welcome the opportunity to continue AIG's work with Hamilton and Two Sigma to become the
        most technology-enabled and capital-efficient carrier in the industry."</p></BodyCopy>