<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BodyCopy><p>Guernsey believes that it can work closely with London to help develop its
        insurance-linked securities (ILS) sector, following findings from a Guernsey roadshow that
        revealed the ILS business in London has been slow to take off. At the roadshow, Guernsey
        practitioners visited lawyers and industry representatives in both London and
        Zurich.&amp;nbsp; </p> <p>Peter Child, managing director of&amp;nbsp;Artex Risk
        Solutions&amp;nbsp;in Guernsey and chairman of the Guernsey International Insurance
        Association's market development committee, said, "We gained the view from those that we
        spoke to [at the road show] that London [may] be seen as complementary to Guernsey's ILS
        sector. While there is demonstrable political will to see the London ILS offering thrive,
        maintaining its insurance sector's reputation as a full-service center capable of delivering
        a full range of insurance and reinsurance services, it is clear that the ILS sector is
        developing fairly slowly.</p> <p>"We believe that Guernsey still holds a number
        of advantages&amp;mdash;the responsiveness of our regulator, our experience in the sector,
        the breadth of our offering in the funds and insurance space, and our status outside of
        Solvency II.</p> <p>"Although London is nominally a competitor, if London can
        make a contribution to drive forward the growth of the ILS market, we think that should be
        good for all involved."</p> <p>The United Kingdom (UK) introduced an ILS regime
        on November 29, 2017. The <a
        href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/regulations-implementing-a-new-regulatory-and-tax-framework-for-insurance-linked-securities"
        target="_blank">regulations</a> aimed to introduce a competitive regulatory and tax
        regime for&amp;nbsp;ILS to ensure that the UK gets a share of this rapidly growing
        market.</p></BodyCopy>
