<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BodyCopy xmlns:cmis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/core/200908/" xmlns:cmisra="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/restatom/200908/" xmlns:sf="urn:telerik:sitefinity:cmis"><p><span style="line-height: 1.5;">Kieran O&amp;rsquo;Mahony of Marsh
        Cayman took over t</span>he chairmanship of the Insurance Managers Association of
        Cayman (IMAC), and a new IMAC Board was elected at its recent 2015 Annual General
        Meeting.&amp;nbsp; </p> <p>The new IMAC Board members are Linda Haddleton
        (Kane), vice chair and chair of Education Committee; Stephen Gray (Willis), treasurer;
        Jennifer Reid (Global Captive Management), secretary; John Pitcairn (Artex), chair of
        Educational Scholarship Foundation; Erin Brosnihan (Kensington), chair of Forum Committee;
        JS de Jager (CSI International), chair of Marketing Committee; Seamus Tivenan (SRS), chair
        of Regulatory and Legislative Committee; and Adrian Lynch (Aon), chair of Research and
        Development Committee.</p> <p>Outgoing Chairperson Rob Leadbetter expressed his
        thanks to his board for their support and hard work over the past 2 years, and he welcomed
        Kieran O&amp;rsquo;Mahony to the chair. &amp;ldquo;As a group, we have accomplished great
        things for Cayman&amp;rsquo;s captive insurance industry and I am confident that under
        Kieran, the association will continue to carry the flag for Cayman and to work tirelessly to
        ensure its continued dominance and strength in the industry,&amp;rdquo; said
        Leadbetter.</p> <p>O&amp;rsquo;Mahony&amp;rsquo;s plans for his term as IMAC
        chairperson include continuing to develop the relationship between industry and legislators
        and regulators, and proactively promoting Cayman&amp;rsquo;s captive insurance industry in
        its existing and new markets. &amp;ldquo;Cayman has an exceptional story to tell &amp;ndash;
        a fantastic product with world-class managers and service providers, and a lengthy history
        of providing an innovative and business-oriented environment that is trusted the world
        round,&amp;rdquo; he said.&amp;nbsp;</p> <p>The Educational Scholarship
        Committee reported that, through its efforts, 27 Caymanian students are now backed by $2.3
        million in IMAC Scholarship funding.&amp;nbsp; </p> <p>View the <a
        href="http://imac.ky/">IMAC website</a>.</p></BodyCopy>