<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BodyCopy xmlns:cmis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/core/200908/" xmlns:cmisra="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/restatom/200908/" xmlns:sf="urn:telerik:sitefinity:cmis"><p>Captive insurance companies&amp;nbsp;continue to attract considerable
        attention from both the National Association of Insurance Commissioners&amp;nbsp;(NAIC) and
        the Internal Revenue Service (IRS), said speakers at the Connecticut Captive Insurance
        Association (CCIA) Symposium on Captive Insurance, which was held October 15, 2015, in
        Stamford, and thus the captive insurance industry should be vigilant in ensuring regulations
        or tax rulings detrimental to captives do not become a problem.<br /> <br />
        That was the takeaway from "A National Perspective: The NAIC and Feds View of Captives,"
        during which Katherine Wade, Connecticut insurance commissioner, and P. Bruce Wright,
        partner at Sutherland Asbill &amp;amp; Brennan LLP, discussed the NAIC's focus on captives
        and recent IRS captive insurance tax cases. The general session followed an opening welcome
        and introduction as 100 attendees gathered for the fourth annual event.<br /> <br
        /> In the afternoon general session, &amp;ldquo;Works of ART: Rationalizing Your Captive
        from Beginning to End,&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp;three speakers gave their
        perspectives&amp;nbsp;from different points in a captive's life cycle. Robert Zorn,
        executive vice president, Red Apple Group, discussed the recent formation of&amp;nbsp;its
        captive. Mark Allitt, director, advisory, KPMG Bermuda, gave insight into
        what&amp;nbsp;captives currently should be doing at the board level. Stephanie Mocatta,
        president, SOBC Corporation, had an interesting&amp;nbsp;presentation on captive failures,
        which typically is not a topic that appears on captive conference agendas.<br />
        &amp;nbsp;<br /> (<a
        href="http://www.irmi.com/products/captive-insurance-company-reports"><em>Captive
        Insurance Company Reports (CICR)</em></a> subscribers in&amp;nbsp;<a
        href="https://www.silverplume.com/sponline/SPSage.aspx?cmd=doc&amp;amp;id=IRM67746">ReferenceConnect</a>
        and&amp;nbsp;<a
        href="https://www.irmi.com/online/cicr/ch000000/2015aug/parallel-universe-of-captives.aspx">IRMI
        Online</a>&amp;nbsp;can learn more in "The Parallel Universe of Captives" in
        the&amp;nbsp;August 2015 issue.)<br /> <br /> There were four breakout sessions,
        as follows.</p> <ul> <li> <p>"The Importance of How&amp;nbsp;You Run
        Your Captive," focused on governance</p> </li> <li> <p>"Creative
        Captive Solutions for Middle and Small Market Companies"</p> </li> <li>
        <p>"The Frontier of Insurance-Linked Securities"</p> </li> <li>
        <p>"Captives as Effective Cost Management Solutions for Health Care"</p>
        </li> </ul> <p>The presentation on insurance-linked securities (ILS) was
        especially illuminating since it highlighted the ILS impact on the reinsurance
        market.&amp;nbsp;(Watch&amp;nbsp;for a report&amp;nbsp;when Captive.com&amp;nbsp;follows
        up&amp;nbsp;with the presenters.)</p> <p> The event actually kicked off the
        night before (October 14, 2015) with the "Idea Factory," a round table
        discussion&amp;nbsp;to generate ideas for expanding the Connecticut captive
        insurance&amp;nbsp;domicile.&amp;nbsp;The group debated how Connecticut could develop a
        market for&amp;nbsp;ILS similar to Bermuda, given the attention the growth in
        the&amp;nbsp;ILS market has received and Connecticut's deep insurance background and
        proximity to the financial center of New York.&amp;nbsp;It was determined that the biggest
        impediment is getting the same tax treatment available in Bermuda.<br /> <br />
        For a small, evolving domicile, the Connecticut symposium should be considered a success
        with its attendance of more than 100.</p></BodyCopy>