<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BodyCopy xmlns:cmis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/core/200908/" xmlns:cmisra="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/restatom/200908/" xmlns:sf="urn:telerik:sitefinity:cmis"><p><strong>By Mike Poskey<br /> President<br />
        </strong><a href="https://www.zeroriskhr.com/">ZERORISK HR,
        Inc.</a></p> <p>Business executives who choose not to use preemployment
        testing in their hiring processes cite a number of reasons for their decisions.
        Unfortunately, four of the most common objections are based on myth instead of reality.
        These are (1) "We'll be sued," (2) "It costs too much," (3) "It takes too much time," and
        (4) "It doesn't work."</p> <p>This article sheds some realistic light on these
        myths to illuminate how integrating preemployment testing into your hiring process can
        increase retention and productivity, as well as decrease the likelihood of employment
        practices lawsuits.</p> <p><strong>Myth #1&amp;mdash;"We'll Be
        Sued."</strong></p> <p>Nowadays, anyone can be sued for anything. However,
        the proper use of testing as a selection tool actually reduces the likelihood of being sued
        for the following three reasons.</p> <ol> <ol> <li>
        <p><strong>The selection process is more fair.</strong> Personal biases of
        interviewers often lead to discrimination claims. Because validated tests do not
        discriminate according to age, sex, race, national origin, or religion, using them can
        reduce subjective biases, making the process more fair for all candidates.</p>
        </li> <li> <p><strong>It helps companies comply with federal
        requirements.</strong> The Equal Employment Opportunity Commission requires that
        companies use "best reasonable efforts" to remove biases from their hiring process. The use
        of an objective validated test helps companies comply with the federal
        requirement.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>You don't hire "problem
        employees."</strong> The greatest risk to an employer is hiring the wrong person. In
        the best case, the person simply doesn't work out and leaves, which is a costly scenario. In
        the worst case, the person steals from you or harasses or injures someone. The liability
        risks of hiring the wrong person are much greater than the risk of being found liable for
        not hiring him or her in the first place. If testing helps you make better hiring decisions,
        you are simply less likely to be sued!</p> </li> </ol> </ol>
        <p>A review of the lawsuits over preemployment testing proves this conclusion true. I
        have been unable to unearth a single court case where a company was found liable because of
        preemployment testing when the test was designed and validated as a selection tool and
        validated to have no adverse impact against a protected class (i.e., race, religion, sex,
        age, national origin).</p> <p>&amp;nbsp;<strong>Myth
        #2&amp;mdash;"Preemployment Testing Costs Too Much."</strong></p> <p>As
        with any business decision, a company must weigh the costs versus the benefits when
        conducting preemployment testing. Most preemployment tests range from $25 to $200 per use.
        Most human resources professionals would agree that the cost of a bad hiring decision that
        results in turnover is at least twice the person's salary when you factor in lost
        opportunity, decreased productivity, and recruitment and administrative costs. Besides the
        obvious costs of making a bad selection decision, a good hiring test can also significantly
        reduce the costs to prepare for an interview and train new hires since your new hires will
        be more suited for the job, company culture, and manager's style.</p> <p>For
        every dollar an employer invests in personnel screening, the savings range from $5 to $16 in
        reduced absenteeism, improved productivity, lower turnover, safer working environments,
        reduced insurance premiums, and decreased employer liability. (Small Business
        Administration.)</p> <p>It will be far less expensive to defend your use of a
        proven, reliable, and valid test than to defend hiring practices that do not include
        objective, nondiscriminatory testing. In addition, it's far less expensive to use testing to
        ensure you hire an employee who will be more productive immediately than to pay your
        managers to oversee problem employees and engage in a revolving-door recruitment
        process.</p> <p><strong>Myth #3&amp;mdash;"It Is Too Time
        Consuming."</strong></p> <p>There are many tests on the market that take
        anywhere from 10 minutes to more than 2 hours to complete. Some require an administrator
        while others do not. However, there are some very good tests that can be completed in
        15&amp;ndash;30 minutes and can be administered via the Internet and completed at home by
        the candidate. Depending on the level and type of position you are trying to fill, some of
        the quicker tests will meet your needs.</p> <p>As for the feedback such tests
        provide, an effectively designed interviewing and selection report substantially reduces the
        time needed to train interviewers and prepare and conduct an interview for the following
        reasons.</p> <ul style="list-style-type: disc;"> <li> <p>An
        effective interviewing report will provide recruiters and department managers guidance on
        key strengths and weaknesses of the candidate to allow them to focus their valuable time on
        the critical areas necessary for success in the respective role/position instead of focusing
        their interview time on less critical areas.</p> </li> <li> <p>An
        effective interviewing report will provide suggested interview questions that are legal to
        ask in an interview.</p> </li> </ul> <p>One executive who currently
        utilizes a behavioral-based preemployment testing program sums it up this way: "It actually
        expedites our interviewing process tremendously by assisting us in cutting to the chase in
        determining a candidate's strengths and weaknesses."</p> <p><strong>Myth
        #4&amp;mdash;"Testing Doesn't Work."</strong></p> <p>More and more
        companies are utilizing some form of behavioral preemployment testing for more consistent
        and accurate hiring decisions. In a recent survey, 40 percent of Fortune 100 companies
        indicated that their employment selection systems included testing. A similar survey by the
        American Management Association showed that 44 percent of its responding members used
        testing to help select employees.</p> <p>Here's what a human resources director
        of a Fortune 500 company in Houston had to say about the preemployment test it uses for
        selection.</p> <p style="margin-left: 40px;">Historically, our industry
        experiences extremely high turnover, and as such we have been looking for a tool to help put
        the right person in the right job. Since we began using a behavioral-based selection tool to
        help in our sales selection process, our retention has jumped from 10 to 77 percent, which
        we have calculated saved us $32 million over the past 12 months in related turnover and lost
        opportunity costs. (HR director, Group 1 Automotive.)</p> <p>If 40 percent of
        the Fortune 100 companies utilize some form of preemployment testing, there must be some
        evidence it works; otherwise, they wouldn't spend the money.</p>
        <p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p> <p>With the unemployment
        rate dropping and the retirement of large numbers of baby boomers, it is becoming more and
        more challenging to find and hire good talent. It is extremely important to make the best
        possible hiring decisions in this type of environment. Doing so requires a top-notch hiring
        process that includes preemployment testing, effective interviewing, and careful reference
        and credential checking (see also "<a
        href="https://www.captive.com/news/2017/04/19/interview-for-success-avoid-legal-pitfalls">Interview
        for Success, and Avoid the Legal Pitfalls</a>").</p>
        <p><strong><em>Mike Poskey</em></strong><em> is
        president of <a href="https://www.zeroriskhr.com/" target="_blank">ZERORISK HR,
        Inc</a>. ZERORISK HR helps organizations build great cultures by identifying, hiring,
        developing, and retaining top talent.</em></p></BodyCopy>