<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BodyCopy xmlns:cmis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/core/200908/" xmlns:cmisra="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/restatom/200908/" xmlns:sf="urn:telerik:sitefinity:cmis"><p>Providing medical stop loss insurance in a captive was one of the hot topics
        at the World Captive Forum 2015.&amp;nbsp;Debbie Liebeskind of Towers Watson, Bruce Wright
        of Sutherland Asbill &amp;amp; Brennan LLP, and Jason Lichtman of JLT Re (North America)
        Inc. addressed this topic in a panel discussion.</p> <p>Medical stop loss
        provides insurance protection to employers self-insuring medical benefits to mitigate the
        risk of large claims or unanticipated claims fluctuation. It can be specific stop loss,
        which essentially caps the amount the employer must pay for large individual claims that may
        occur, or aggregate stop loss to protect against an aggregation of claims in a year
        exceeding some stipulated amount.&amp;nbsp;The U.S. marketplace for this coverage is about
        $5 billion per year.</p> <p>The Affordable Care Act increased the need for this
        protection by eliminating some of the protections that employers could specifically build
        into their plans in the past. Specifically, they can no longer impose annual or lifetime
        maximums on the protection provided to employees.</p> <p>Coverage is available
        from medical carriers and direct writers of medical stop loss. Generally the premiums
        charged by the direct writers&amp;nbsp;are significantly (e.g., 30 percent) less than those
        charged by medical carriers.</p> <p>Importantly, the medical reinsurance
        marketplace is even larger than the stop loss marketplace. As a result, reinsurance charges
        are even less than those of the direct writers. Reinsurance for a given client might be 50
        percent less than the premium that would be charged by a medical carrier and significantly
        less than the premium that a direct writer might charge. The problem for employers is that
        it is available only as reinsurance, and they cannot access the market directly. </p>
        <p>Enter captives. As an insurer, a captive can buy the reinsurance and take advantage
        of the lower cost. In addition to the lower cost, there are other potential advantages. It
        is not yet settled whether this insurance will qualify as unrelated business. If this is
        eventually accepted by the Internal Revenue Service,&amp;nbsp;it could provide owners of
        single-parent captives with a mechanism to deduct all premiums paid to their captives. Using
        the captive may also increase the organization&amp;rsquo;s ability to retain more of this
        risk and thereby cut costs further. </p> <p>Of course, there are also negatives.
        The first is the administrative and related costs associated with accounting, setting up
        agreements, filing a revised business plan with the captive&amp;rsquo;s regulator,
        purchasing the reinsurance, and the like. Depending on the jurisdiction, there may be a
        small premium tax or a direct payment premium tax payable. But the cost savings will offset
        these negatives for most large employers. </p> <p>Unlike employee benefit plans,
        it is generally not necessary to file a medical stop loss insurance program with the U.S.
        Department of Labor to obtain an Employee Retirement Income Security Act&amp;nbsp;exemption.
        The reason is that the insurance is covering the employer&amp;rsquo;s risk (of claims
        exceeding some retention) and not providing any type of benefit directly for employees. To
        preserve this, it is necessary that the employees not be required to contribute to the cost
        of the stop loss coverage.</p> <p>An important caveat to consider before setting
        up one of these programs is the need&amp;nbsp;to evaluate the captive owner&amp;rsquo;s
        situation with respect to deductibility of premiums paid to the captive. If the owner has
        justified the deduction of premiums paid based on the fact that the captive writes unrelated
        third-party business, including the stop loss coverage may change the mix of related versus
        unrelated business if this type of insurance is at some point deemed to be related business.
        </p> <p>In summary, this is an innovative cost control solution that should be
        considered by captive owners. Of course, it will be necessary&amp;nbsp;to carefully
        review&amp;nbsp;the pros and cons, but for many large employers it will likely make
        sense.<br /> <br /> The World Captive Forum 2015, held February 1-4 in Boca
        Raton, Florida, was attended by nearly 300 captive owners, managers, reinsurers, and other
        service providers.<br /> <br /> <em>(Pictured in the photo above are, from
        right, Ms. Liebeskind, Mr. Lichtman, Mr. Wright, and Hugh Rosenbaum, Towers Watson, who
        served as panel moderator.)</em></p></BodyCopy>