<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BodyCopy xmlns:cmis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/core/200908/" xmlns:cmisra="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/restatom/200908/" xmlns:sf="urn:telerik:sitefinity:cmis"><p>Marsh has appointed key leaders for its regional, specialty, and placement
        teams worldwide to be effective upon closing of the transaction between Marsh &amp;amp;
        McLennan Companies (MMC) and JLT Group, subject to certain approvals.</p>
        <p><strong>Marsh International</strong></p> <p>All
        international regional leaders will report to Flavio Piccolomini, president of Marsh
        International.</p> <ul> <li><span style="font-size: 13px;">Chris Lay
        will continue as CEO of the United Kingdom and Ireland. Adrian Girling, currently chairman
        of United Kingdom, Europe, and South Africa for JLT, will become chairman of United Kingdom
        and Ireland corporate and risk management for Marsh and report to Mr.
        Lay.</span></li> <li><span style="font-size: 13px;">Nick Harris, CEO
        of Australia and New Zealand for JLT, will become CEO of Pacific for Marsh. Scott Leney,
        currently Marsh Pacific CEO, will become CEO for Australia and report to Mr. Harris. Andre
        Louw, currently chairman of Australia and New Zealand for JLT, will become chairman of
        Pacific for Marsh.</span></li> <li><span style="font-size:
        13px;">Christos Adamantiadis will continue as CEO of Middle East and Africa (MEA).
        Peregrine Towneley, currently CEO of MEA for JLT, will become chairman of Middle East for
        Marsh. Robert Makhoul, currently Marsh &amp;amp; McLennan Companies chief client officer and
        chairman of Middle East for Marsh, will continue as MMC chief client officer for the Middle
        East.</span></li> <li><span style="font-size: 13px;">David Jacob
        will continue as CEO of Asia. Alan Cheah will continue as chairman of Asia. James
        Addington-Smith, currently Asia specialty leader for Marsh, will become CEO of ASEAN, a
        subregion of Asia, reporting to Mr. Jacob.</span></li> <li><span
        style="font-size: 13px;">Siegmund Fahrig will continue as CEO of Continental
        Europe.</span></li> <li><span style="font-size: 13px;">Ricardo
        Brockmann will continue as CEO of Latin America.</span></li> </ul>
        <p><strong>Marsh United States and Canada</strong></p> <p>As
        previously announced, Martin South, president of Marsh United States and Canada, will
        continue to lead the region. Sarah Robson will continue as CEO of Canada, reporting to Mr.
        South.</p> <p><strong>Marsh-JLT Specialty</strong></p>
        <p>As previously announced, Dominic Burke, CEO of JLT Group, in addition to becoming
        vice chairman of Marsh &amp;amp; McLennan Companies and a member of the MMC Executive
        Committee, will become chairman of Marsh-JLT Specialty. Lucy Clarke will become president of
        Marsh-JLT Specialty reporting to John Doyle, president and CEO of Marsh. Global specialty
        leaders will report to Ms. Clarke. Regional specialty leaders will report both to Ms. Clarke
        and their respective regional leader.</p> <p><em><strong>Global
        Specialty Leaders</strong></em></p> <ul> <li><span
        style="font-size: 13px;">Simon Harker, currently global aviation and space leader for
        Marsh, will become global head of aviation.</span></li> <li><span
        style="font-size: 13px;">Richard Gurney, currently global head of construction for JLT,
        will become global head of construction.</span></li> <li><span
        style="font-size: 13px;">Nick Robson, currently global head of credit, political and
        security risk for JLT, will become global head of credit specialty. Evan Freely, currently
        global credit specialty leader for Marsh, will become deputy global head of credit
        specialty, reporting to Mr. Robson.</span></li> <li><span
        style="font-size: 13px;">Andrew George, currently global industry specialty leader for
        Marsh, will become global head of energy and power. Jim Pierce, currently global head of
        energy, power, and mining for JLT, will become chairman of global energy and
        power.</span></li> <li><span style="font-size: 13px;">Mark Wood,
        currently global head of financial lines for JLT, will become head of financial and
        professional lines (FINPRO) international.</span></li> <li><span
        style="font-size: 13px;">Devin Beresheim, currently US FINPRO practice head for Marsh,
        will become head of FINPRO United States and Canada.</span></li>
        <li><span style="font-size: 13px;">Marcus Baker, currently global marine leader
        for Marsh, will become global head of marine.</span></li> <li><span
        style="font-size: 13px;">Karen Beldy Torborg, currently Marsh's global private equity and
        mergers and acquisitions (PEMA) and infrastructure leader, will become global head of PEMA
        and infrastructure.</span></li> </ul>
        <p><em><strong>Regional Specialty
        Leaders</strong></em></p> <ul> <li><span style="font-size:
        13px;">Pat Donnelly, currently CEO of the United States for JLT Specialty, will become
        head of Marsh-JLT Specialty for United States and Canada.</span></li>
        <li><span style="font-size: 13px;">Paul Moody, currently Marsh United Kingdom
        and Ireland Specialty leader, will become head of Marsh-JLT Specialty for the United Kingdom
        and Ireland. Roy White, currently chairman of United Kingdom&amp;nbsp;Specialty for Marsh,
        will become chairman of Marsh-JLT Specialty for the United Kingdom and
        Ireland.</span></li> <li><span style="font-size: 13px;">Paul
        Knowles, currently CEO of United Kingdom, Europe, and South Africa for JLT, will become head
        of Marsh-JLT Specialty in Continental Europe.</span></li> <li><span
        style="font-size: 13px;">Josh Roach, currently Marsh Specialty leader for Pacific, will
        become head of Marsh-JLT Specialty for Pacific.</span></li> <li><span
        style="font-size: 13px;">Dominic Samengo-Turner, currently CEO of Asia for JLT, will
        become head of Marsh-JLT Specialty in Asia.</span></li> <li><span
        style="font-size: 13px;">Peter Foley, currently Marsh retail placement and specialty
        leader in Latin America, will become head of Marsh-JLT Specialty for Latin
        America.</span></li> <li><span style="font-size: 13px;">Gaurav
        Bhatnagar, currently Marsh retail placement and specialty leader in Middle East and Africa,
        will become head of Marsh-JLT Specialty in MEA.</span></li> </ul>
        <p><strong>Marsh Global Placement</strong></p> <p>As
        previously announced, Dean Klisura will become president, Marsh global placement,
        responsible for placement protocols and standards across all lines within Marsh, and he will
        lead nonspecialty placement operations including Bowring Marsh and existing multiline
        placement hubs. Regional placement leaders will continue in their current positions
        reporting to Mr. Klisura and to their respective regional leader, including John Donnelly,
        global placement leader for Asia and Pacific; Nick Holmes, global placement leader for
        Continental Europe and Middle East and Africa; Carlos Rivera, global placement leader for
        Latin America; Andrew Chester, global placement leader for the United Kingdom and Ireland;
        and Chris Lang, global placement leader for United States and Canada. Tom Davies, global
        wholesale placement leader for Marsh, will continue in that role leading Bowring Marsh and
        reporting to Mr. Klisura.</p></BodyCopy>