<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BodyCopy xmlns:cmis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/core/200908/" xmlns:cmisra="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/restatom/200908/" xmlns:sf="urn:telerik:sitefinity:cmis"><p>International Risk Management Institute, Inc. (IRMI), has opened registration
        for the <a href="https://www.irmi.com/conferences/agribusiness-conferences"
        target="_blank">2020 IRMI Emmett J Vaughan Agribusiness Conferences (AgriCon)</a>.
        These three regional Conferences are focused on the unique exposures faced by farms and
        other agribusinesses and how to best construct the insurance programs that cover
        them.</p> <p>The 2020 AgriCon locations and dates are as follows.</p>
        <ul> <li>Sacramento, California&amp;mdash;March 8&amp;ndash;10</li>
        <li>Richmond, Virginia&amp;mdash;June 16&amp;ndash;17</li> <li>Des Moines,
        Iowa&amp;mdash;September 15&amp;ndash;16</li> </ul> <p>"Through the
        Agribusiness Conferences, Agribusiness and Farm Insurance Specialist (AFIS&amp;reg;)
        certification program, a new comprehensive online reference&amp;mdash;<em>Agribusiness
        Risk and Insurance (ARI), </em>and our recently launched free e-newsletter,
        <em>IRMI AgriRisk</em>, we are committed to continuing development and
        enhancement of educational content and resources that address the unique exposures and risk
        management challenges faced by farms, ranches, and other agribusinesses," said IRMI
        President and CEO Jack P. Gibson. "Participating in IRMI AgriCon is a great way for agents,
        brokers, underwriters, and insurance buyers to discover best practices for agribusiness risk
        management and stay ahead of new exposures."</p> <p>A highlight of this year's
        Conferences will be keynote addresses from top-ranking government officials who will present
        an overview of their state's current agribusiness climate. The following dignitaries are
        currently scheduled to speak. </p> <ul> <li>Sacramento&amp;mdash;Secretary
        Karen Ross, California Department of Food and Agriculture</li>
        <li>Richmond&amp;mdash;Commissioner Jewel Bronaugh, Virginia Department of Agriculture
        and Consumer Services </li> <li> Des Moines&amp;mdash;Secretary Mike Naig, Iowa
        Department of Agriculture and Land Stewardship </li> </ul> <p>Another
        featured event will be "Market and Cultural Pressures,"<strong> </strong>a lunch
        panel discussion and open forum addressing issues faced by the farming community and how
        they impact insurance coverage. Wayne Holt, Nationwide director of farm underwriting; "Rudy"
        Rudolph, AFIS instructor and rancher; and Dr. Cie Freeman, immediate past president of the
        Los Angeles County Medical Association, will share insights on the trials of farmers and
        ranchers in the current climate and political environment, stress they cause, insurance
        implications, and available resources to address these challenges.</p> <p>Each
        Conference will also feature multiple sessions covering hot-button topics such as climate
        change, wildfires, and agribusiness claims. Featured speakers and sessions include the
        following.</p> <ul> <li> Best-selling author Rob Galbraith, Chartered
        Property Casualty Underwriter, will present on blockchain, agribusiness technology, and
        InsurTech. </li> <li> Camille Dixon, statewide program manager and cannabis
        insurance external affairs director for the California Department of Insurance, will provide
        attendees with a "Cannabis and Hemp State of the Market Update." </li> <li> John
        Talley, juris doctor, Missouri Department of Commerce and Insurance captive program manager,
        will review the use of captive insurance as it relates to agriculture. </li>
        </ul> <p>Attendees can also choose to take classes that lead to obtaining and
        maintaining the <a
        href="https://www.irmi.com/certifications/agribusiness-farm-insurance-specialist"
        target="_blank">Agribusiness and Farm Insurance Specialist (AFIS&amp;reg;)
        certification</a>, the foremost continuing education program for specialists in
        agricultural and farm risk management and insurance. Find the <a
        href="http://www.irmi.com/AgriCon" target="_blank">full agendas for each
        Conference</a>.</p> <p>Providing fun entertainment and a chance for
        attendees to have a good laugh will be Greg Peterson of the Peterson Farm Brothers. Known
        for hilarious and entertaining award-winning videos and songs about farm life that have
        racked up over 50 million views on YouTube, Mr. Peterson will share his unique outlook on
        family farms and the future of the agricultural industry.</p> <p>To learn more
        or to register, visit <a href="https://www.irmi.com/AgriCon"
        target="_blank">https://www.irmi.com/AgriCon</a> or call (800)
        827&amp;ndash;4242.</p> <p><strong>About IRMI</strong> <br />
        For more than 40 years, IRMI has helped save lives and livelihoods as the premier provider
        of risk management and insurance information, tools, education, and training. IRMI helps
        risk management, insurance, and legal professionals make better decisions for their
        companies and clients with unbiased expertise and balanced comprehensive content. For more
        information, visit <a
        href="https://www.irmi.com/">https://www.irmi.com</a>.</p> <p>
        <strong>Contact:</strong> Heidi Vincent, (800)
        827&amp;ndash;4242</p></BodyCopy>