<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BodyCopy xmlns:cmis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/core/200908/" xmlns:cmisra="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/restatom/200908/" xmlns:sf="urn:telerik:sitefinity:cmis"><p>Most captives were probably unaware that InsureTech hosted its <a
        href="http://www.insurancejournal.com/news/national/2016/10/06/428534.htm">first
        </a><a
        href="http://www.insurancejournal.com/news/national/2016/10/06/428534.htm">annual
        conference</a>&amp;nbsp;October 5&amp;ndash;6, 2016, in Las Vegas. The first
        InsureTech Connect 2016 conference had an estimated 1,500 attendees. From around the world,
        tech entrepreneurs, investors, and insurance executives met to discuss the impact of
        technology on the future of the insurance industry. </p> <p>Andrew Simpson
        attended the event and filed a report, &amp;ldquo;<a
        href="http://www.insurancejournal.com/news/national/2016/10/17/429441.htm">10 Takeaways
        from the Future of Insurance and InsureTech Connect Conference</a>,&amp;rdquo; for the
        <em>Insurance Journal</em> on October 17, 2016.</p>
        <p>&amp;ldquo;What follows are some impressions from the busy two-day conference.
        These in no way reflect all of the ideas or themes at the conference&amp;mdash;only those
        from sessions I attended and people I cornered. I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet figured out how to
        be in more than one place at a time, although I would not be surprised if there is a
        technology to allow that,&amp;rdquo; Mr. Simpson writes in the article.</p>
        <p>The following are Mr. Simpson&amp;rsquo;s 10 takeaways from the
        conference.</p> <ul> <li>Agents and brokers, although facing significant
        disruptions to their business model, will survive. Smart agents/brokers will migrate to
        areas where they can add real value, for instance, large commercial risks.</li>
        <li>The most disruptive players in property/casualty, such as the peer-to-peer (P2P)
        company Lemonade, may be what are known as &amp;ldquo;full stack&amp;rdquo; companies. These
        companies are interested in replacing the existing legacy insurers with new business models
        instead of building upon systems that are already in place.</li> <li>While P2P
        models are interesting, they are unlikely to be a large player in the evolving
        market.</li> <li>Traditional insurers are very active in the InsureTech
        scene.</li> <li>InsureTech will prosper because the current insurance industry
        is over-expensed, marred by inefficiencies and inadequate use of data, according to Brian
        Duperreault, CEO of Hamilton Insurance Group.</li> <li>Behavioral science will
        significantly impact the way insurers interact with clients, particularly in personal
        lines.</li> <li>Telematics will be important, especially as they migrate into
        commercial auto.</li> <li>Companies must embrace change and build
        trust.</li> <li>The use of third-party data to improve underwriting and claims
        will add value, as the &amp;ldquo;big data&amp;rdquo; juggernaut will continue.</li>
        <li>Companies need to become more &amp;ldquo;customer&amp;rdquo; focused and design
        products that meet their needs.</li> </ul></BodyCopy>