<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BodyCopy xmlns:cmis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/core/200908/" xmlns:cmisra="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/restatom/200908/" xmlns:sf="urn:telerik:sitefinity:cmis"><p>The Captive Insurance Companies Association (CICA) has announced the program
        for its 2015 International Conference, which will be held March 8&amp;ndash;10, 2015 in
        Orlando, Florida.</p> <p>The conference theme<em>, </em>"The
        Strategic Advantage," sets the stage to identify and explore innovative uses of captives to
        address issues such as cyber and reputational risk or harnessing big data to improve risk
        management results.</p> <p>"In today's technology-driven, highly connected
        environment, everything changes and moves faster than even just a few years ago. This
        constant change brings increased opportunities to look at new and innovative uses of
        captives to provide the strategic advantage businesses are looking for," says CICA President
        Dennis Harwick. "We've put together a well-balanced program designed to offer valuable
        insights and new ideas for industry veterans and newcomers," Harwick
        added.&amp;nbsp;</p> <p>The CICA International Conference program opens on
        Monday, March 9, with a general session, awards presentations, and a keynote address by Jack
        Uldrich,&amp;nbsp;a renowned global futurist and the author of 11 books. Uldrich is the
        founder and "chief unlearning officer" of the School of Unlearning&amp;mdash;an
        international leadership, change management, and technology consultancy dedicated to helping
        businesses and organizations prepare for and profit from periods of profound
        transformation.</p> <p>Conference program highlights
        include:&amp;nbsp;</p> <ul> <li> <p>New Business Strategy: Designing
        and Implementing a Cyber Risk Insurance Program</p> </li> <li>
        <p>Insuring Reputation: A Risk of Risks</p> </li> <li>
        <p>CICA's Best Practices and Strategies for Transfer Pricing</p> </li>
        <li> <p>Developing the Operational Strategy of Managing Medical Stop Loss in
        Your Captive</p> </li> <li> <p>Big Data and Captives: Using Data and
        Dashboards to your Strategic Advantage</p> </li> </ul> <p><span
        style="line-height: 1.5;">Additional sessions include "New Developments in State and
        Federal Income Taxes," "Using Reinsurance to Make Strategic Decisions for Your Captive
        Structure," "How to Understand and Get the Most Out of Your Actuarial Report," "A Strategic
        Advantage to Developing Next Generation Captive Professionals," "How to Manage Employee
        Benefit Risk, A Canadian and U.S. Perspective," and much more.&amp;nbsp;<a
        href="http://www.cicaworld.com/EventsEducation/EventsIntConf/ProgramSchedule.aspx"
        target="_blank">See the full program</a></span><span style="line-height:
        1.5;">. The Opening General Session features the presentation of the industry's two
        highest honors: the 2014 CICA Distinguished Service Award and the Outstanding Captive Award.
        Plan to be there for these exciting and inspiring presentations.</span></p>
        <p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Jk9W_QKCSns"
        target="_blank">Preview</a>&amp;nbsp;one of keynote speaker Jack Uldrich's futurist
        presentations on YouTube. </p> <p>Representatives of Captive.com will be
        attending and reporting on the CICA conference.</p></BodyCopy>