<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BodyCopy xmlns:cmis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/core/200908/" xmlns:cmisra="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/restatom/200908/" xmlns:sf="urn:telerik:sitefinity:cmis"><p>Mark Twain (but also attributed to Gideon Tucker) is quoted as having said,
        "No man's life, liberty or property are safe while the Legislature is in session." This will
        be especially true when Congress convenes in the new year and considers tax reform. Tax
        reform was a hot topic during the recent election, and the Republican majority in the House
        of Representatives is already gearing up to advance some significant changes in Federal tax
        law.</p> <p>One outcome of tax reform is there are almost always winners and
        losers. What impact might tax reform have on captives? Will tax reform have no impact on
        captives, or will they be winners or losers? </p> <p>Rather than speculate on
        what the impact might be, here are three recommendations to all those working in the captive
        insurance industry or interested in the future of it.</p> <ul> <li>
        <p>Take the time to understand the tax reform process.</p> </li>
        <li> <p>Be proactive in supporting the advocacy efforts of Captive Insurance
        Companies Association, the Self-Insurance Institute of America, and your state captive
        association. </p> </li> <li> <p>Communicate with your US congressman
        and senator.</p> </li> </ul> <p>To help with the first step in
        understanding the tax reform process, read <em><a
        href="https://home.kpmg.com/content/dam/kpmg/xx/pdf/2016/12/tnf-faq-on-tax-reform-final.pdf"
        target="_blank">Understanding the Tax Reform Process: FAQ</a></em>, which
        KPMG published December 5, 2016. It is a great primer that will provide readers with an
        understanding of the following.</p> <ul> <li> <p>Legislative process
        and timing</p> </li> <li> <p>Prospects for tax reform</p>
        </li> <li> <p>Key players</p> </li> <li> <p>The
        substance of tax reform and other useful insights</p> </li> </ul>
        <p>The US Constitution requires that all bills regarding taxation must originate in
        the House of Representatives. The House Committee on Ways and Means is the chief tax-writing
        committee, and House procedure is that all bills regarding taxation must go through this
        committee. For that reason, communications with persons serving on that committee are
        especially important when taxation or revenue measures are under consideration. The chairman
        of that committee is Rep. Kevin Brady, a Republican from Texas's 8th District. The ranking
        member of the Democrats is Rep. Sander Levin, representing Michigan's 9th District. A <a
        href="https://waysandmeans.house.gov/about/committee-members" target="_blank">complete
        listing of members of the Ways and Means Committee</a> can be found on the committee
        website.</p> <p> It is worth ending this article by repeating Mr. Twain's (or
        Mr. Tucker's) quote, "No man's life, liberty or property are safe while the Legislature is
        in session." Be prepared to understand the process and what, if any effects, tax reform
        proposals will have on captives.</p></BodyCopy>