<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BodyCopy xmlns:cmis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/core/200908/" xmlns:cmisra="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/restatom/200908/" xmlns:sf="urn:telerik:sitefinity:cmis"><table cellspacing="0" border="0" width="100%"> <tbody> <tr>
        <td> <div>New York</div> </td> </tr> <tr> <td
        style="height: 10px;"></td> </tr> <tr> <td> <div>
        <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> Fitch Ratings has affirmed the ratings of Validus Holdings,
        Ltd. (Validus). These rating actions include Validus's senior unsecured debt rating, which
        was affirmed at "BBB+," and the insurer financial strength (IFS) rating of
        Validus&amp;nbsp;Reinsurance, Ltd. (Validus Re), which was affirmed at "A." The rating
        outlook is stable. A complete list of rating actions is provided at the end of this article.
        <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> <strong>Key Rating Drivers</strong>
        <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> Validus's ratings reflect the company's continued solid
        operating performance and internal capital generation since its inception in late 2005.
        Validus reported $316 million of net earnings in the first half of 2014, driven by a strong
        combined ratio of 68.5 percent, which benefited from the absence of large catastrophe events
        during the period. <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> In addition, the ratings reflect Fitch's
        negative sector outlook on global&amp;nbsp;reinsurance, as the fundamentals of
        the&amp;nbsp;reinsurance&amp;nbsp;sector have deteriorated with declining premium pricing
        and weakening of terms and conditions. This has been particularly the case for property
        catastrophe risk, Validus's largest individual line of business that represented
        approximately one-third of total company gross premiums written in 2013.
        <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> Validus has responded to increased price competition by
        reducing its risk exposure, with property catastrophe gross premiums written down
        16&amp;nbsp;percent&amp;nbsp;in the first half of 2014 as compared to the first half of
        2013. Validus has also reduced its per event probable maximum losses (PMLs) for most
        catastrophe perils, on an absolute basis and as a percent of total equity. Fitch expects
        that Validus will continue to maintain underwriting discipline should future market
        conditions continue to deteriorate. <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> The ratings affirmation
        reflects that the company's underwriting performance, while potentially volatile, continues
        to compare favorably to other&amp;nbsp;reinsurers&amp;nbsp;with a property catastrophe focus
        rated by Fitch when viewed on a multiyear rolling average basis. This is due, in part, to
        the company's growing diversification into specialty&amp;nbsp;reinsurance&amp;nbsp;lines,
        Talbot operations within Lloyds, and, more recently, its AlphaCat alternative capital
        segment. <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> Fitch observes that the company's share of global
        catastrophe losses since its inception, while significant in some cases, has been manageable
        and consistent with levels that might be expected from a&amp;nbsp;reinsurer&amp;nbsp;of
        Validus's size and focus. <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> Fitch believes that Validus uses
        sound risk management processes to manage its exposure to potential catastrophe-related
        losses by geographic zone and relative to its capital base. Validus's low underwriting
        leverage enables the company to preserve capital during periods that include underwriting
        volatility. <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> Validus's capital ratios (such as net premium to
        equity and assets to equity) have consistently remained well within tolerances for the
        current rating level. Fitch expects this trend to continue for the foreseeable future.
        <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> Validus's ratings were unaffected by the company's June 2014
        announcement that it plans to acquire Western World&amp;nbsp;Insurance&amp;nbsp;Group
        (Western World) for $690 million in cash. Western World is a New Jersey-based privately held
        property-casualty insurer that focuses on casualty risks in the excess and surplus lines
        market. <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> Fitch expects the transaction, which Validus plans to
        fund with cash on hand, to result in negligible changes to the company's financial and
        operating leverage. After closing, expected in the fourth quarter of 2014, the company's
        consolidated debt-to-capital ratio is anticipated to remain near recent levels in the
        mid-teens while net written premiums-to-equity ratio should remain close to levels of around
        0.5x reported by Validus in each of the past several years. <p>&amp;nbsp;</p>
        <strong>Rating Sensitivities</strong> <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> Key rating
        triggers that could generate longer term positive rating pressure include a prolonged period
        during which Validus outperformed comparably rated peers with respect to underwriting
        performance and overall profitability, continued strong risk adjusted capitalization
        metrics, and enhanced competitive positioning and scale in the company's key product lines.
        <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> Key rating triggers that could lead to a downgrade include
        continued deterioration in market conditions in Validus's core business lines that impair
        the company's ability to sustain its historically strong profitability. Specifically,
        failure to maintain a multiyear average combined ratio of 90&amp;nbsp;percent&amp;nbsp;or
        better could result in a ratings downgrade. <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> Other key rating
        triggers that could result in a ratings downgrade include an increase in underwriting
        leverage (measured by traditional net premiums written to equity ratios) to levels at or
        above 0.8 times (x) from recent levels of 0.5x. Likewise, an increase in Validus's
        1&amp;ndash;100 and 1&amp;ndash;250 year per event catastrophe PMLs to
        30&amp;nbsp;percent&amp;nbsp;(currently 17&amp;nbsp;percent) and
        40&amp;nbsp;percent&amp;nbsp;(currently 23&amp;nbsp;percent) of total equity, respectively,
        could result in a downgrade. <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> Fitch could also downgrade the
        company's ratings if Validus were to suffer catastrophe losses that were unfavorably
        inconsistent with its own internally modeled results or that resulted in earnings and/or
        capital declines that were significantly worse than comparably rated peers.
        <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> A material increase in Validus's debt-to-capital ratio to
        levels in excess of 25&amp;nbsp;percent&amp;nbsp;or decrease in interest coverage ratios to
        the low single digits for a period of consecutive years could lead Fitch to downgrade the
        company's debt ratings. <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> Fitch has affirmed the following
        ratings with a stable rating outlook. <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> Validus Holdings, Ltd.
        <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> --Issuer default rating at "A-" <p>&amp;nbsp;</p>
        --$250 million of 8.875&amp;nbsp;percent&amp;nbsp;senior unsecured notes due 2040 at "BBB+"
        <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> --$150 million of 9.07&amp;nbsp;percent&amp;nbsp;junior
        subordinated deferrable debentures due June 2036 at "BBB-" <p>&amp;nbsp;</p>
        --$140 million of 8.48&amp;nbsp;percent&amp;nbsp;junior subordinated deferrable debentures
        due June 2037 at "BBB-" <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> Validus&amp;nbsp;Reinsurance, Ltd.
        <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> --IFS at "A" <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> Additional
        information is available at <a
        href="http://cts.businesswire.com/ct/CT?id=smartlink&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.fitchratings.com&amp;amp;esheet=50927174&amp;amp;newsitemid=20140819005898&amp;amp;lan=en-US&amp;amp;anchor=www.fitchratings.com&amp;amp;index=1&amp;amp;md5=cdf84a743e673baed42922fd2d09bee7">www.fitchratings.com</a>.
        <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> Applicable Criteria and Related Research:
        <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> --Insurance&amp;nbsp;Rating Methodology (November 2013)
        <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> Applicable Criteria and Related Research:
        <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> <a
        href="http://www.fitchratings.com/creditdesk/reports/report_frame.cfm?rpt_id=723072">Insurance&amp;nbsp;Rating
        Methodology</a> <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> Additional Disclosure
        <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> <a
        href="http://www.fitchratings.com/gws/en/disclosure/solicitation?pr_id=853675">Solicitation
        Status</a><br /> <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> <p>&amp;nbsp;</p> ALL
        FITCH CREDIT RATINGS ARE SUBJECT TO CERTAIN LIMITATIONS AND DISCLAIMERS.&amp;nbsp;<a
        href="HTTP://FITCHRATINGS.COM/UNDERSTANDINGCREDITRATINGS">PLEASE READ THESE LIMITATIONS
        AND DISCLAIMERS BY FOLLOWING THIS LINK</a>. IN ADDITION, <a
        href="WWW.FITCHRATINGS.COM">RATING DEFINITIONS AND THE TERMS OF USE OF SUCH RATINGS ARE
        AVAILABLE ON THE AGENCY'S PUBLIC WEBSITE</a>. PUBLISHED RATINGS, CRITERIA, AND
        METHODOLOGIES ARE AVAILABLE FROM THIS SITE AT ALL TIMES. FITCH'S CODE OF CONDUCT,
        CONFIDENTIALITY, CONFLICTS OF INTEREST, AFFILIATE FIREWALL, COMPLIANCE, AND OTHER RELEVANT
        POLICIES AND PROCEDURES ARE ALSO AVAILABLE FROM THE "CODE OF CONDUCT" SECTION OF THIS SITE.
        FITCH MAY HAVE PROVIDED ANOTHER PERMISSIBLE SERVICE TO THE RATED ENTITY OR ITS RELATED THIRD
        PARTIES. DETAILS OF THIS SERVICE FOR RATINGS FOR WHICH THE LEAD ANALYST IS BASED IN AN
        EU-REGISTERED ENTITY CAN BE FOUND ON THE ENTITY SUMMARY PAGE FOR THIS ISSUER ON THE FITCH
        WEBSITE.<br /> <br /> <br /> <br /> CONTACT: Fitch Ratings<br
        /> Primary Analyst<br /> Greg Dickerson<br /> Director<br />
        +1&amp;ndash;212&amp;ndash;908&amp;ndash;0220<br /> Fitch Ratings, Inc.<br /> 33
        Whitehall Street<br /> New York, NY 10004<br /> or<br /> Secondary
        Analyst<br /> Brian Schneider<br /> Senior Director<br />
        +1&amp;ndash;312&amp;ndash;606&amp;ndash;2321<br /> or<br /> Committee
        Chairperson<br /> Jeff Mohrenweiser<br /> Senior Director<br />
        +1&amp;ndash;312&amp;ndash;368&amp;ndash;3182<br /> or<br /> Media
        Relations:<br /> Brian Bertsch, +1&amp;ndash;212&amp;ndash;908&amp;ndash;0549 (New
        York)<br /> <a
        href="mailto:brian.bertsch@fitchratings.com">brian.bertsch@fitchratings.com</a></div>
        </td> </tr> </tbody> </table></BodyCopy>