<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BodyCopy xmlns:cmis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/core/200908/" xmlns:cmisra="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/restatom/200908/" xmlns:sf="urn:telerik:sitefinity:cmis"><p>Michael Sapnar, president and CEO of Transatlantic Reinsurance Company and
        past chair of the Reinsurance Association of America (RAA), testified on May 2, 2017, before
        the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs in support of the <a
        href="https://www.captive.com/news/2017/01/17/state-insurance-regulation-supported-in-u.s.-eu-agreement"
        target="_blank">US-EU covered agreement</a>. Mr. Sapnar testified on behalf of the
        American Insurance Association, the American Council of Life Insurers, the Council of
        Insurance Agents and Brokers, and the RAA. In his testimony, Mr. Sapnar stressed the
        importance of signing the covered agreement as negotiated, highlighting that if the
        agreement is not signed, US companies will be unable to renew (much less write) any new
        business in the European Union without first going through the regulatory processes
        necessary to create branches or subsidiaries in multiple EU member states&amp;mdash;a
        process that requires time and significant cost. </p> <p>Frank Nutter, president
        of the RAA, said, "Mike's testimony reinforces the fact that US and EU negotiators worked
        tirelessly over the last year to achieve a bilateral agreement to address important
        prudential reinsurance and insurance matters. The agreement ensures domestic and foreign
        (re)insurers are treated equally, and will help to resolve uncertainties in the global
        (re)insurance market." </p> <p> Mr. Nutter went on to say, "The RAA looks
        forward to working with Chairman Crapo and the committee to alleviate concerns that have
        been raised about the agreement so that it can be promptly signed by both jurisdictions in
        the near term."</p></BodyCopy>