<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BodyCopy xmlns:cmis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/core/200908/" xmlns:cmisra="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/restatom/200908/" xmlns:sf="urn:telerik:sitefinity:cmis"><p>Lloyd's will require each syndicate to write no less than 40 percent of its
        risks using a&amp;nbsp;"recognized electronic placement system" for the first quarter of
        2019, increasing to 50 percent for the second quarter of 2019. Lloyd's said a quote target
        will also be introduced in second quarter 2019, and all targets will now apply to both lead
        and follow business.</p> <p>To support electronic risk placement adoption across
        the market, Lloyd's brokers will also be required to connect to a recognized electronic
        placement platform by June 1, 2019. </p> <p>The mandate was issued in the first
        quarter of 2018 following discussions with members of the Lloyd's market, the Lloyd's Market
        Association, the London &amp;amp; International Brokers' Association, and the International
        Underwriting Association. </p> <p>Designed to accelerate the market's digital
        transformation and to ensure the market realizes the benefits of electronic placement, the
        mandate has already driven impressive adoption across the Lloyd's market, Lloyd's
        said.</p> <p>Lloyd's chief operating officer, Shirine Khoury-Haq, said, "Since
        we implemented this mandate across the Lloyd's market, we've seen a marked increase in the
        adoption of electronic trading, which is fast-tracking our [digital] transformation. The
        latest developments, including quote targets and the Lloyd's broker requirement, are
        essential next steps in our journey to digitise our market.&amp;hellip;"</p> <p>
        By the end of 2018's third quarter, Lloyd's said 29.8 percent of "in scope" contracts were
        placed electronically in the Lloyd's market and almost reached the 30 percent fourth-quarter
        target. Syndicates meeting and exceeding the targets receive a rebate on their annual
        subscriptions, according to Lloyd's.<br /> <br /> Currently, all classes of
        business are available on the electronic placing platform provided by Placing Platform
        Limited, with 58 brokers and 124 insurers signed up as of November 30,
        2018.</p></BodyCopy>