<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BodyCopy xmlns:cmis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/core/200908/" xmlns:cmisra="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/restatom/200908/" xmlns:sf="urn:telerik:sitefinity:cmis"><p>Jonathan Reiss is joining captive management and consulting firm Strategic
        Risk Solutions (SRS) as managing director and as a member of the board.</p>
        <p>Mr. Reiss, who is currently president of strategic partnerships at Hamilton
        Insurance Group, Ltd., in Bermuda, is expected to join SRS during this year's fourth
        quarter. He will assume responsibility for several of the company's expansion initiatives,
        primarily focused in the commercial insurance and reinsurance sector.</p> <p>Mr.
        Reiss has more than 27 years of insurance industry experience and is one of the founders of
        Hamilton, having previously served as its group chief financial officer. He currently
        oversees a variety of Hamilton's strategic initiatives, including Hamilton ILS, Hamilton's
        syndicate management business at Lloyd's, and certain InsurTech joint venture
        interests.</p> <p>"I am excited to have someone of Jonathan's caliber and
        experience join the firm," Brady Young, president and CEO of SRS, said in a statement. "We
        have enjoyed consistently strong growth in our core captive management and consulting
        business including expansion of those businesses geographically. We also believe there are
        opportunities to provide more services to commercial insurers and reinsurers as well as
        developing new products, services, and risk capital to support our existing captive client
        base.</p> <p>"Jonathan will play a lead role in helping us evaluate these
        opportunities and, where appropriate, to implement solutions," Mr. Young said.</p>
        <p>"I am thrilled to be joining the terrific team at SRS and in a role that builds on
        my prior experiences," Mr. Reiss said in the statement. "SRS is a leader in the captive
        management industry, and as the largest independent manager, is the best alternative to the
        broker owned managers.</p> <p>"Because of its impressive client base and broad
        insurance manager and risk management capabilities, SRS is uniquely well positioned to
        expand into complementary areas of the broader insurance industry," Mr. Reiss
        said.</p> <p> Mr. Reiss will be based in Bermuda but will be engaged in firm
        activities worldwide.</p></BodyCopy>