<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BodyCopy xmlns:cmis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/core/200908/" xmlns:cmisra="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/restatom/200908/" xmlns:sf="urn:telerik:sitefinity:cmis"><p>The United States and European Union recently signed the <a
        href="https://www.treasury.gov/initiatives/fio/reports-and-notices/Documents/US_EU_Covered_Agreement_Signed_September_17.pdf"
        target="_blank">bilateral EU-US agreement on prudential insurance and reinsurance
        measures</a>.&amp;nbsp; </p> <p>The agreement&amp;mdash;which is a
        "covered agreement" in the meaning of the Dodd-Frank Act for the United States and an
        agreement under Article 218 of the Treaty on the Functioning of the European
        Union&amp;mdash;addresses three areas of prudential insurance oversight: reinsurance, group
        supervision, and the exchange of insurance information between supervisors.</p>
        <p>The agreement will lead to the elimination of collateral and local presence
        requirements for US and EU reinsurers operating in each other's markets.</p>
        <p>By virtue of the agreement, US and EU insurers operating in the other's markets
        will only be subject to worldwide prudential insurance group oversight by supervisors in
        their home jurisdiction.&amp;nbsp;</p> <p>The agreement also encourages
        insurance supervisory authorities in the United States and the European Union to continue to
        exchange supervisory information on insurers and reinsurers that operate in the US and EU
        markets. To support such information exchange between supervisory authorities, the agreement
        includes model information sharing memorandum of understanding provisions.</p>
        <p>The agreement represents a major step forward in US-EU cooperation on insurance and
        reinsurance, conveying benefits to US and EU insurers and reinsurers operating across the
        Atlantic by offering them enhanced regulatory certainty while maintaining robust consumer
        protections.</p> <p>US Trade Representative Robert Lighthizer said, "The
        Agreement with the EU levels the playing field for the US insurance industry, thereby
        strengthening American competitiveness in the EU. The Agreement, which will be implemented
        consistent with the US policy statement, promotes US interests by protecting consumers here
        at home and relieving US insurers of compliance with potentially redundant EU regulatory
        requirements."</p> <p>Read the text of the <a
        href="https://ustr.gov/sites/default/files/files/US%20Covered%20Agreement.pdf"
        target="_blank">US policy statement</a> and the <a
        href="https://ustr.gov/about-us/policy-offices/press-office/press-releases/2017/september/joint-statement-upcoming"
        target="_blank">joint US-EU statement</a> on the signing of the covered
        agreement.</p> <p>For more about the agreement, see the Captive.com articles
        "<a
        href="https://www.captive.com/news/2017/07/18/ready-to-grow-insurer-opportunities-united-states-set-to-sign-covered-agreement">Ready
        To Grow Insurer Opportunities, United States Set To Sign Covered Agreement</a>,"
        "<a
        href="https://www.captive.com/news/2017/06/09/european-council-agrees-to-sign-eu-us-covered-agreement">European
        Council Agrees To Sign EU-US Covered Agreement</a>," "<a
        href="https://www.captive.com/news/2017/05/19/rims-backs-treasury-dept-us-eu-covered-reinsurance-agreement">RIMS
        Backs Treasury Department's US-EU Covered Agreement on Reinsurance</a>," "<a
        href="https://www.captive.com/news/2017/05/05/transatlantic-re-ceo-testifies-support-of-covered-agreement">Transatlantic
        Re CEO Michael Sapnar Testifies in Support of Covered Agreement</a>," "<a
        href="https://www.captive.com/news/2017/03/22/insurance-industry-trades-voice-covered-agreement-support">Insurance
        Industry Trades Voice Support for Covered Agreement</a>," and "<a
        href="https://www.captive.com/news/2017/01/17/state-insurance-regulation-supported-in-u.s.-eu-agreement">State
        Insurance Regulation Supported in US-European Union
        Agreement</a>."</p></BodyCopy>