<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BodyCopy xmlns:cmis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/core/200908/" xmlns:cmisra="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/cmis/restatom/200908/" xmlns:sf="urn:telerik:sitefinity:cmis"><p>Another major organization, the University of Vermont (UVM) Health Network in
        Burlington, has redomiciled its medical malpractice captive insurer, VMC Indemnity Company,
        Ltd. (VMCIC), from Bermuda to <a
        href="https://www.captive.com/domiciles/vermont-captive-domicile-summary">Vermont</a>.</p>
        <p>"Our analysis showed that relocating to Vermont had become less expensive than
        previously anticipated and an attractive option&amp;mdash;one that we are happy to embrace,"
        Dr. John Brumsted, president and CEO of the UVM Health Network and a VMCIC board member,
        said in a statement.</p> <p>"We are pleased to be able to do business locally
        and be part of Vermont's world-class captive insurance industry," Dr. Brumsted
        added.</p> <p>The relocation of the captive, which was first licensed in Bermuda
        in 1993, was applauded by Vermont Governor Phil Scott.</p> <p>"It's great to see
        the UVM Health Network take this step and to count them among the growing list of academic
        medical center and health care captive organizations located in Vermont," Governor Scott
        said in a statement.</p> <p>The UVM Health Network joins a growing number of
        organizations that have moved their captives to Vermont from other domiciles. Currently, 94
        captives, <a
        href="https://www.captive.com/news/2019/07/24/captives-no-longer-alternative-market-vermont-david-provost">said
        David Provost, Vermont's deputy commissioner of captive insurance</a> in Montpelier,
        have relocated to Vermont since the state became a captive domicile following the passage of
        authorizing legislation in 1981. That is far more than any other domestic
        domicile.</p> <p> Organizations, Mr. Provost said in an earlier interview with
        Captive.com,&amp;nbsp;"Move their captives here for the stability we have here. Vermont is
        known as a long-term domicile. We are not going anywhere. We don't change with political
        winds. It is a big deal that Vermont has remained a solid, stable captive
        domicile."</p> <p>The healthcare industry is a major source of the new captives
        being set up in Vermont. In 2018, for example, 6 of the 25 new captives licensed in 2018 in
        Vermont were set up by organizations in the healthcare industry.</p> <p>"The
        continued growth of hospitals and doctors' groups forming Vermont captives for medical
        professional liability coverage has been very positive," Ian Davis, Vermont's director of
        financial services, said in a statement at the time Vermont released its 2018 captive
        formations statistics.</p> <p> At the end of 2018, Vermont had 580 captives,
        making it, by far, the largest domestic domicile.<br /> <br /> </p>
        <p><span style="font-size: 30px; font-family: 'Titillium Web', sans-serif; color:
        #1f497d;">Related Videos</span></p> <hr style="background:#264c84;
        border:0; height: 4px;" /> <ul> <li> <a
        href="https://www.captive.com/captive-videos/video-pages/medical-professional-liability-captives-physician-migration">Part
        I: Medical Professional Liability in Captives and Physician Migration</a></li>
        <li><a
        href="https://www.captive.com/captive-videos/video-pages/medical-professional-liability-captives-population-management">Part
        II: Medical Professional Liability in Captives and Population
        Management</a></li> <li><a
        href="https://www.captive.com/captive-videos/healthcare-liability-captives-a-significant-segment-of-captive-industry">Healthcare
        Liability Captives a Significant Segment of the Captive Industry</a></li>
        <li><a
        href="https://www.captive.com/captive-videos/healthcare-liability-captives-play-a-role-in-improving-patient-care">Healthcare
        Liability Captives Play a Role in Improving Patient Care</a></li>
        <li><a
        href="https://www.captive.com/captive-videos/healthcare-liability-captives-thrive-in-soft-professional-liability-market">Healthcare
        Liability Captives Thrive in a Soft Professional Liability Market</a></li>
        </ul></BodyCopy>