<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="../ConfigFiles/captive.css"?>
<article id="b01e4bde-0e2e-645a-bd90-ff0000ef0c73">
    <h1>Formal Performance Review Best Practices</h1>
    <p class="summary">Managers who are effective at reviewing others' performance understand how
        essential the formal performance review process is, prepare carefully, and do a thorough
        job. Managers who are not particularly effective avoid this part of their role, push it off
        onto others, or do a poor job.</p>
    <p><strong>By Mike Poskey</strong><br/>
        <strong>President</strong><br/>
        <strong>ZERORISK HR, Inc.</strong><br/>
    </p>
    <p> Reviewing performance is a critical competency for a manager to be effective, yet it also
        can be difficult. Most employees care about how their performance is perceived by
        management. Naturally, they resist and dislike being told that they either committed errors
        or are not capable in certain areas. Managers who are effective at reviewing others'
        performance understand how essential the formal performance review process is, prepare
        carefully, and do a thorough job. Managers who are not particularly effective avoid this
        part of their role, push it off onto others (usually human resources or an assistant
        manager), or do an incomplete job.</p>
    <p>Most workplace surveys show that great employers have the following in common.</p>
    <ul>
        <li>Management makes their expectations clear.</li>
        <li>Management provides training and development opportunities to employees.</li>
        <li>Management's actions match their words.</li>
        <li>Employees are given responsibility.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>The perfect opportunity for a manager to communicate clear expectations, outline training and
        development opportunities, and establish goals and related responsibilities is in the
        performance review process. However, the standard once-a-year performance review is flawed
        because of the following.</p>
    <ul>
        <li> Managers typically don't like having to prepare the usually lengthy document and spend
            time to actually conduct the review. </li>
        <li> The review meetings make employees (and sometimes managers) nervous. </li>
        <li> Meeting once a year doesn't build consistent feedback and coaching into the process. </li>
        <li> The review meeting becomes a "data dump," especially for immature or inexperienced
            managers. </li>
        <li> The whole process tends to be a subjective "judging" act that doesn't clearly define
            success, expectations, and growth opportunities. </li>
    </ul>
    <p>Essentially, two kinds of performance reviews exist: informal and formal reviews. A manager
        informally reviews someone's work when he or she talks about the person's performance in an
        unstructured, soon-after-the-fact meeting. While it may be scheduled, it is essentially a
        review concerning a specific task or how the person handled a particular incident. Formal
        reviews are scheduled (usually once a year) and are typically done by all managers during
        the same time period in the year. They are designed to review the person's performance for
        an entire year and are "official." Typically, a written report is produced and entered into
        the person's personnel file. This article will focus on best practices and recommendations
        for conducting and leading formal performance reviews.</p>
    <p>While there's no "map" to conducting a perfect formal review, there are many nuggets of
        advice to be considered by those in management who may not be particularly comfortable with
        doing them. Some of these follow.</p>
    <p>
        <strong>No Surprises</strong>
    </p>
    <p>If the employee is surprised by something he or she is told in a formal review, then the
        manager has not been communicating enough during the year. Look for surprise on the
        employee's face. Ask whether he or she saw this coming, and if not, perhaps go over some
        indications that may have served as red flags to unacceptable performance.</p>
    <p>
        <strong>Let the Employee Talk First</strong>
    </p>
    <p>Because most people judge themselves more harshly than anyone else does, it is a good idea
        for the manager to ask the employee to give his or her assessment of the job the employee
        has done over the year. After hearing from the employee, the manager will have an idea of
        how the employee views his or her performance and only then does the manager have an
        accurate platform from which he or she can effectively coach and encourage the employee.</p>
    <p>
        <strong>Write It Down, and Have the Information Peer-Reviewed</strong>
    </p>
    <p>Before the meeting, write down what must be clearly communicated to the employee and the
        results/outcomes that are expected and desired. Also, have these expectations reviewed by a
        peer manager or by an HR representative. Many people only "hear" things that are in
        writing.</p>
    <p>
        <strong>When It's Not a Great Review, Let Your Written Outline Sit</strong>
    </p>
    <p>Write the poor review and sit on it for at least 2 days before reviewing it again. It's
        always a good idea to write it and then rewrite it after you have had a few days to sleep on
        it. While this is good counsel for anyone who is angry or disappointed, it is especially
        true for a formal performance review. In this setting, the manager is directly affecting the
        employee's job, career, and often his or her compensation, so the content of this meeting
        can have a significant impact on the person's sense of confidence and morale.</p>
    <p>
        <strong>Do Not Postpone the Meeting</strong>
    </p>
    <p>It is very common for managers to postpone formal performance reviews for one of two reasons:
        either they do not want to do them, or they believe that little loss is experienced if the
        meeting is postponed. But employees are usually anxious about their reviews and have told
        loved ones and friends about their upcoming review and therefore are either embarrassed or
        frustrated when their review is delayed.</p>
    <p>
        <strong>Acknowledge Unacceptable Performance</strong>
    </p>
    <p>Do not let unacceptable performance or behavior go unstated or unwritten. Another common
        mistake managers make is to not address unwanted behavior or poor performance in this
        setting. But, if not here, then where? Failing to give honest feedback in the formal review
        might postpone the inevitable confrontational discussion, but it also sets the discussion up
        to be even more confrontational when it finally occurs.</p>
    <p>
        <strong>Take the Lead throughout the Entire Meeting</strong>
    </p>
    <p>While you may have the employee talk first, always remember that it is your meeting. The
        manager sets the agenda and the tone. If the employee needs to complain, explain things, or
        set the record straight, these things are permissible within a meeting that you are running.
        You have specific things that you need to communicate and accomplish. While it is important
        for the employee to feel that he or she has been heard and honored in this meeting, make
        sure that you walk away from every formal performance review with a high degree of comfort
        that you accomplished your goals as well.</p>
    <p>
        <strong>Do Away with Subjective Grading</strong>
    </p>
    <p>Many companies have a review process that entails having the manager assign a subjective
        grade to various competencies or performance indicators. An example would be assigning a
        score of 1–5 (5 being the best) for a competency, such as communication. This subjective
        grading opens the door for disagreement between the manager and the employee and most often
        lends itself to demotivating the employee. Have you ever heard managers say, "I never give a
        score of a 5 because there is always room for improvement"? If so, then that manager has
        just demotivated the employee.</p>
    <p>
        <strong>Step 1 Toward a Best Practice Performance Review Process</strong>
    </p>
    <p>As a way to incorporate all of the aforementioned best practices, a three-step process is
        recommended.</p>
    <p>Have each manager provide the following questions to each of the manager's direct reports and
        give them about a week or so to write down their answers. These questions should include
        employee self-evaluation questions, such as the following.</p>
    <ul>
        <li> What does success in my position look like to me? (Each manager needs to determine what
            the success gap is based on the manager's definition of success for the employee.) </li>
        <li> What are my expectations of my manager and of the company? (Unmet expectations are the
            source of contempt and lowered morale.) </li>
        <li> What are the things I do well in this position? (This reveals what the employee views
            are his or her strengths.) </li>
        <li> What are the things that keep me from doing my best in this position? (Development
            opportunities will be discovered.) </li>
        <li> What does my manager do well? (This indicates how to best manage the employee.) </li>
        <li> What gets in my manager's way? (This gives insight about the employee's unique
            motivators and the manager's development opportunities.) </li>
    </ul>
    <p>
        <strong>Step 2 Toward a Best Practice Performance Review Process</strong>
    </p>
    <p>Have each manager answer the following questions about each of his or her direct reports. The
        content from the following four questions is what should be documented in the formal review
        form. The manager's perspective questions include the following.</p>
    <ul>
        <li> What does success in the employee's position look like to me? (Include outcomes/target
            goals that are observable and measurable. An example of this may be something like
            "Achieving 100 percent of your sales quota" for a salesperson.) </li>
        <li> What are my expectations of the employee? (These are the things the employee does on a
            daily, weekly, monthly, and quarterly basis to achieve the desired outcomes/target
            goals. This may be driven from the core competencies of each job title, such as
            communication, sales appointments, teamwork, community involvement, etc. The key here is
            to use action-oriented language stating what you actually see the employee doing. An
            example of this may be something like "I envision you going out on five sales
            appointments with prospects each week.") </li>
        <li> What are the things I do well in this position? (Include the employee's strengths from
            the manager's perspective.) </li>
        <li> What are the things that hamper me in this position? (Include growth and development
            opportunities—refrain from using the term "weaknesses.") </li>
    </ul>
    <p>
        <strong>Step 3 Toward a Best Practice Performance Review Process</strong>
    </p>
    <p>A series of three brief meetings is recommended in the process of communicating the
        information and ultimately establishing the formal performance review document. After the
        employee has completed his or her self-evaluation, the manager should sit down with the
        employee and listen to the results of his or her self-evaluation. The manager is only
        listening in this meeting, and if the manager talks, it is only to confirm what the employee
        is trying to communicate—that is, to clarify.</p>
    <p>The next meeting, which is recommended to occur about 1 week from the first meeting, is for
        the manager to communicate his or her answers to the manager's perspective questions to the
        employee.</p>
    <p>The manager then takes the answers from both the employee's self-evaluation and the manager's
        perspective questions and merges them into one final performance document.</p>
    <p>The manager schedules a third meeting with the employee to confirm and sign off on the
        performance outcomes and expectations for the upcoming year. It is recommended that the
        overall goals/outcomes or action items include some of those identified by the employee so
        the employee has ownership of his or her annual goals. This also eliminates the potential
        for the employees to state that they had no input regarding their annual goals.</p>
    <p>Afterward, it is recommended that the manager and employee meet on a quarterly basis to
        revisit the desired outcomes and process goals to confirm that the employee is on track to
        achieve these annual goals. This constant communication eliminates "surprises" and provides
        an opportunity for the manager to coach the employee throughout the year on any process
        goals or expectations that aren't being met.</p>
    <p>
        <strong>Metric for Salary Increases</strong>
    </p>
    <p>Implementing the suggestion that there be no subjective scoring process on various
        performance indicators will likely throw a wrench into the process used by many companies to
        determine annual salary increases. One alternative is to use a percentage of overall
        outcomes/target goals achieved to drive salary increases rather than using a subjective
        score for various performance indicators. For example, if, based on the manager's definition
        of success for the employee, there are 10 outcomes/target goals, and the employee achieves 7
        of those at the end of the year, then the employee receives a performance grade of 70
        percent. You may wish to develop something similar to the following guide to develop salary
        increases.</p>
    <p>
        <strong>Overall Outcomes Achieved/Salary Increase Percentage</strong>
    </p>
    <p>85–100% = 3.00% salary increase </p>
    <p>70–84% = 2.00% salary increase </p>
    <p>55–69% = 1.00% salary increase </p>
    <p>0–54% = 0% salary increase </p>
    <p>
        <strong>Conclusion</strong>
    </p>
    <p>In summary, the best practices and three-step process recommended in this article help change
        the annual performance review from a systemic judging act to an extrinsic and intrinsic
        coaching process and help managers clearly define success and communicate their
        expectations. Additionally, they outline training and development opportunities while
        reducing anxiety and defensiveness. The process allows the employee to take ownership in his
        or her annual goals, and it creates a performance document so the manager and employee are
        working from the same set of expectations.</p>
    <p>
        <i>Mike Poskey is president of </i><a href="https://www.zeroriskhr.com/"><i>ZERORISK HR, Inc</i></a><em>. ZERORISK HR helps organizations build great cultures by identifying, hiring, developing, and retaining top talent.</em>
    </p>

</article>
