<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="../ConfigFiles/captive.css"?>
<article id="c7ab50de-0e2e-645a-bd90-ff0000ef0c73">
    <h1>Key Concepts for Captive Insurance Reinsurance Contracts</h1>
    <p class="summary">We take a look at some key concepts and reinsurance contract clauses that can
        help minimize the likelihood of a disagreement with your reinsurers. And, should these
        disagreements arise, the concepts and contract wording can provide additional protection to
        a captive insurance company.</p>
    <p>We start by asking an open question of all the captive owners and board members who read
            <em>Captive Wire</em>. Have you read your reinsurance contracts in their entirety? Do
        you understand all of the sections and language used? Do you know whether there are any
        differences in conditions that exist between your reinsurance contracts and your own
        coverage documents? If you answered no to our question, who has read them on your behalf,
        and have they reported any issues you should be concerned about? Having just been part of a
        rather lengthy case involving a reinsurance dispute, this editor thinks an article on key
        concepts for reinsurance contracts is warranted.</p>
    <p>International Risk Management Institute, Inc. (IRMI), publisher of Captive.com and <i>Captive
            Wire</i>, offers a series of <a
            href="https://www.irmi.com/expert-commentary?taxonomy=topics&amp;propertyName=category&amp;taxon=%2finsurance-industry-topics%2freinsurance"
            >Expert Commentary articles</a> on reinsurance. For those seeking a basic understanding
        of the complexities associated with reinsurance, we suggest this is an excellent starting
        point. The purpose of this article is to focus on some of the key concepts concerning
        reinsurance contracts and what captive insurers should be cognizant of when entering into a
        contract. This piece is not intended to be all-inclusive, nor should you rely on it as the
        final authority of any reinsurance contract wording. For that, we would recommend the use of
        a good reinsurance broker and/or reinsurance attorney.</p>
    <p>For purposes of this discussion, we are going to focus on four key elements associated with a
        reinsurance contract, as follows.</p>
    <ul>
        <li> The doctrine of utmost good faith </li>
        <li> The potential conflict between underwriting submissions and reinsurance contract
            wording </li>
        <li> The "follow the fortunes" concept </li>
        <li> The "follow the settlements" concept </li>
    </ul>
    <p>Most of today's reinsurance contracts also contain arbitration clauses, which purportedly are
        intended to reduce the costs of litigation when conflicts do arise. Since we covered these
        in detail in a <a
            href="https://www.captive.com/news/2017/11/08/reinsurance-arbitration-clause-pitfalls-for-captive-insurers"
            >previous article</a>, we won't add them to our list above. Suffice it to say, captive
        insurers need to make sure they truly understand how their reinsurance arbitration clause
        operates and under what ground rules.</p>
    <p>
        <strong>The Doctrine of Utmost Good Faith</strong>
    </p>
    <p>The doctrine of utmost good faith has been applied as a standard of conduct for reinsurance
        transactions for a long time. The concept, as it applies, is intended to establish the
        guidelines the ceding party (i.e., the entity seeking coverage), in this case the captive
        insurer, must follow when placing business with the assuming company, in this case the
        reinsurer. It flows from the idea that the party seeking coverage has the best understanding
        of the risk being reinsured. Therefore, the burden rests on the captive insurer to provide
        all information that may have a bearing on the risk being underwritten to the reinsurer. The
        two areas where this doctrine typically causes friction between the parties is the initial
        placement submission and when claims are filed.</p>
    <p>In beginning the application process for reinsurance or when submitting a claim against an
        existing reinsurance contract, a captive insurer should seek to answer two basic questions,
        as follows.</p>
    <ul>
        <li> Have we truthfully disclosed all material facts concerning the risk being underwritten
            or the claim being submitted? </li>
        <li> And, if there is any information we haven't disclosed, why are these facts not deemed
            relevant to either the underwriting submission or the claim? </li>
    </ul>
    <p>In both cases, but especially with claims, this is where a coverage opinion provided by an
        experienced reinsurance attorney can be invaluable. A good attorney will look to ensure the
        captive has followed all the established procedures when handling the claim as part of the
        process.</p>
    <p>
        <strong>Placement Submission and Reinsurance Contract Wording</strong>
    </p>
    <p>As we noted above, one area where the doctrine of utmost good faith comes into play is in the
        initial underwriting and issuance of a reinsurance contract. Captive insurers should play
        close attention to the reinsurance placement submissions that are sent to their current or
        potential reinsurance partners. </p>
    <p>In many instances, the captive's reinsurance broker develops these reinsurance submissions,
        typically with input from the captive. Regardless of whether the broker asks for input from
        you, it is imperative that you see and read the reinsurance submission before it is
        submitted on your behalf to reinsurers. The penalty for failure to disclose any material
        facts can be the voidance of the contract by the reinsurer. Reinsurers can seek this remedy
        even in instances where the captive innocently misrepresented a material fact. Therefore,
        the more eyes that review the submission, particularly from the captive, the better.</p>
    <p>An example of innocent misrepresentation concerns lines of business covered in treaty
        reinsurance. In a submission to the reinsurer, the captive indicates it does not currently
        intend to underwrite a line of business and therefore is not seeking coverage. However, when
        the treaty is issued, the line of business in question is included in the coverage. No one
        catches the discrepancy. Several years go by with the treaty being renewed with no changes.
        For some reason, most often driven by a policyholder, the captive decides to add coverage
        for the line of business it did not offer. In checking the treaty, the business line shows
        as covered and therefore no additional disclosure is made to the reinsurer. Then a claim
        arises that involves a reinsurance recovery. Does the reinsurer pay the claim since the
        treaty includes coverage, or does it deny the claim under the context that the captive
        indicated in its submission it did not write this type of coverage and never notified the
        reinsurer when the change was made?</p>
    <p>
        <strong>Follow the Fortunes Concept</strong>
    </p>
    <p>The "follow the fortunes" clause is a reinsurance doctrine that states the business fortunes
        of the reinsurer will follow the fortunes of the captive the company has agreed to reinsure.
        Typically, captives will look to have "follow the fortunes" language inserted into their
        reinsurance contract as a condition of the reinsurance. In doing so, the clause is intended
        to assure the reinsurers will follow the business decisions and fortunes of the captive as
        they arise in the normal course of business.</p>
    <p>Where the reinsurer agrees to the insertion of a "follow the fortunes" clause in the
        contract, it is widely understood within the industry that the clause provides protection to
        the ceding company, in this case the captive. This protection amounts to the reinsurer
        agreeing to be party to the captive's underwriting and management of the business lines
        being reinsured through both good and bad results. Obviously, the captive and the reinsurer
        are mostly concerned with poor results due to unexpected or adverse loss developments.</p>
    <p>However, an equally important corollary doctrine has evolved concerning the reinsurer's
        deference to the captive's claims-related business decisions and payments. Captives
        typically assume that the inclusion of the "follow the fortunes" clause is sufficient to
        ensure the reinsurer will provide coverage and payments on all claims the captive settles
        covered under the contract. While some courts have agreed with this interpretation, a better
        alternative for the captive is to include the additional "follow the settlements"
        clause.</p>
    <p>
        <strong>Follow the Settlements Concept</strong>
    </p>
    <p>The "follow the settlements" clause requires a reinsurer to afford its cedents'
        claims-related business decisions deference and may bind the reinsurer to the captive's
        objectively reasonable and good faith claims payments or settlement decisions. A follow the
        settlements clause can provide the captive with a wide degree of protections, including
        requiring immediate payment of any claim. </p>
    <p>Given the unique relationship captive insurers have with their members and owners, a follow
        the settlements clause in their reinsurance contract provides additional protection that the
        reinsurer will be obligated to pay claims presented by the captive. It is important to note
        though that even here, the first concept we talked about, "utmost good faith," comes into
        play. While the captive has a vested interest in making sure all reasonable claims presented
        by its members are paid, it also must do so in a way that maintains this good faith
        requirement with its reinsurer.</p>
    <p>Hopefully, all of your dealings with your reinsurance partners will be free from any
        disagreements. But by following these doctrines and having these clauses within your
        reinsurance contract, you can lessen the likelihood of these disagreements
        materializing.</p>
    <p> Copyright &amp;copy; 2018, International Risk Management Institute, Inc. </p>
</article>
