<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article SYSTEM "../ConfigFiles/captive.dtd">
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="../ConfigFiles/captive.css" title="Bootstrap CSS" alternate="no"?>
<article>
    <h1>RAA Reports Improvement in US Reinsurers' Operating Results</h1>
    <p class="summary">The latest Reinsurance Association of America (RAA) survey reveals that a
        group of 18 US property-casualty reinsurers wrote $30.1 billion of net premiums during the 6
        months ended June 30, 2018, compared to $22.5 billion for the same period in 2017.</p>
    <p>The latest Reinsurance Association of America (RAA) survey reveals that a group of 18 US
        property-casualty reinsurers wrote $30.1 billion of net premiums during the 6 months ended
        June 30, 2018, compared to $22.5 billion for the same period in 2017. The combined ratio for
        the group was 96.1 percent, improving from 97.1 percent for the same period in 2017. The
        combined ratio is attributable to a 70.0 percent loss ratio versus 72.8 percent for the same
        period in 2017 and a 26.1 percent expense ratio versus 24.3 percent for the same
        period in 2017. Policyholders' surplus was $170.5 billion, compared to $165.2 billion at
        March 31, 2018.</p>
    <p>According to the RAA website, the <em>RAA Reinsurance Underwriting Report</em> presents the
        cumulative quarterly underwriting and operating results of major US property-casualty
        reinsurers and includes premiums, losses, underwriting and expense ratios, and other
        financial results, including the following interactive report sections.</p>
    <ul>
        <li>Quarterly underwriting report</li>
        <li>Profitability scatter graph</li>
        <li>Change in net written premium heat map</li>
        <li>Underwriting ratio analysis graph</li>
        <li>Gross written premium compared to net written premium graph</li>
        <li>Combined ratio ranking graph</li>
        <li>Premium report</li>
        <li>Underwriting report</li>
        <li>Income reports</li>
    </ul>
    <p>Visit the RAA's website to view the 6-month underwriting reports for 2018 and 2017 in the
            <em>Quarterly Underwriting and Operating Report.</em> Each section of the report may be
        downloaded as a PDF file and printed.</p>
</article>
